Man : THEY CALLED THEM " THE HAUNTED SHORES , "
THESE STRETCHES OF DEVONSHIRE AND CORNWALL AND IRELAND ,
WHICH REAR UP AGAINST THE WESTWARD OCEAN .
MISTS GATHER HERE , AND SEA FOG , AND EERIE STORIES .
THAT 'S NOT BECAUSE THERE ARE MORE GHOSTS HERE
THAN IN OTHER PLACES , MIND YOU ,
IT 'S JUST THAT PEOPLE WHO LIVE HEREABOUTS ARE STRANGELY AWARE OF THEM .
YOU SEE , DAY AND NIGHT , YEAR IN , YEAR OUT ,
THEY LISTEN TO THE POUND AND STIR OF THE WAVES .
THERE 'S LIFE AND DEATH IN THAT RESTLESS SOUND ,
AND ETERNITY TOO .
IF YOU LISTEN TO IT LONG ENOUGH ,
ALL YOUR SENSES ARE SHARPENED .
YOU COME BY STRANGE INSTINCTS .
YOU GET TO RECOGNIZE A PECULIAR COLD ,
WHICH IS THE FIRST WARNING .
THE COLD WHICH IS NO MERE MATTER OF DEGREES FAHRENHEIT ,
BUT A DRAINING OF WARMTH IN THE VITAL CENTERS OF THE LIVING .
LOCAL PEOPLE TELL ME THEY WOULD HAVE FELT IT ,
EVEN OUTSIDE THAT LOCKED DOOR .
WE DIDN 'T .
THEY CAN 'T UNDERSTAND WHY WE DIDN 'T KNOW WHAT IT MEANT
WHEN OUR DOG WOULDN 'T GO UP THOSE STAIRS .
ANIMALS SEE THE BLASTED THINGS , IT APPEARS .
MY SISTER PAMELA AND I KNEW NOTHING ABOUT SUCH MATTERS- -
NOT THEN , WE DIDN 'T .
WE HAD THE DISADVANTAGE OF BEING LONDONERS ,
JUST DOWN FOR A FORTNIGHT 'S REST .
THAT 10TH DAY OF MAY , 1937 ,
WAS THE END OF OUR HOLIDAY .
( barking )
WE SEEM TO BE IN SOMEBODY 'S GARDEN .
WHAT WAS SOMEBODY 'S GARDEN .
WHAT A MARVELOUS OLD HOUSE .
BETTER GET OUT BEFORE WE 'RE HAD UP FOR TRESPASSING .
WHERE ON EARTH DID WE LEAVE THE CAR ?
THAT DIRECTION , I THINK .
LOOK , A SQUIRREL .
- Man : GRAB BOBBY ! - TOO LATE ! BOBBY , COME BACK HERE !
( barks )
Pam : YOU BAD DOG !
BOBBY !
RICK , HE 'S GOT THE POOR LITTLE SQUIRREL TRAPPED .
- HE 'LL KILL IT . - MY DEAR SWEET SISTER ,
IT 'S MORE LIKELY HE 'S HAVING HIS WAY WITH OUR BOBBY .
( barking )
Rick : FINE WAY TO SPEND A HOLIDAY- - CHASING A DOG !
- Pam : WHERE IS HE ? - Rick : UNDER HERE , I THINK .
OWW !
I THOUGHT YOU HAD HIM .
HAD ME . THERE HE GOES ! HANG ON TO BOBBY !
I CAN 'T !
( barks )
Rick : WELL PLAYED , SIR .
- DO YOU SUPPOSE HE CAN GET OUT ? - CERTAINLY . HE 'S ON THE ROOF BY NOW .
THAT 'S A SMART DOG .
HE 'LL BE BACK ANY MINUTE .
RICK , HAVE YOU NOTICED ANYTHING ?
ONLY THAT I 'M IN NO SHAPE TO JOIN THE HUNTING SET .
NO , I MEAN THIS HOUSE .
IT 'S THE LOVELIEST THING I EVER SAW .
LOOK AT THAT STAIRCASE .
OH , BOY , WHAT BANISTERS FOR SLIDING .
- OH , RICK . - WHAT IS IT ?
YOUR SAYING THAT , AND THE HOUSE- - IT TOOK ME BACK .
- YEAH , IT 'S QUITE A BIT LIKE- - - THE ROSE BOWL THERE ,
THE GRANDFATHER CLOCK THERE ,
AND MOTHER IN HER BEST GRAY MOIRE
SWEEPING DOWN THE STAIRS .
YOU 'LL BE HOWLING IN A MINUTE . COME ON OUT .
NOT ON YOUR LIFE . I 'M GOING TO SEE THE REST OF THIS .
COME ON , RICK , LET 'S PRETEND WE 'RE BUYING IT .
I 'LL TOSS YOU FOR THE BEDROOM WITH THE BEST VIEW .
THEY 'VE ALL GOT BEST VIEWS .
HOW LOVELY .
WHY DOES IT MAKE ME FEEL LIKE I 'M ON A BOAT ?
IT 'S THE LIGHT ON THE CEILING . THAT 'S THE SEA .
IT 'S NICE TO WAKE UP AND SEE THAT .
OH , HOW I DO HATE LIVING IN A LONDON FLAT .
I SUPPOSE IF YOU 'RE BROUGHT UP IN AN OLD HOUSE ,
YOU ALWAYS HANKER FOR ONE .
IT 'S STUCK . YOU TRY IT .
IT 'S LOCKED . FAMILY SKELETONS , PROBABLY .
OH , WHAT A BORE .
RICK , THE BATHROOM .
OPEN FIRE WHILE YOU BATHE .
WHAT LUXURY .
( chuckles )
YOU KNOW , THIS IS A SATURDAY-NIGHT-ONLY BATHROOM .
YOU BOIL YOURSELF AS RED AS A LOBSTER
THEN HURRY TO BED TO AVOID A CHILL .
- RICK . - WHAT ?
I 'VE HAD ONE OF MY " FEELINGS . "
WE 'RE REALLY GOING TO BUY THIS HOUSE .
OH , YES ? DID YOUR FEELING TELL YOU WHAT YOU 'RE GOING TO BUY IT WITH ?
WELL , IF WE BOTH PUT IN EVERYTHING WE HAVE ,
MAYBE WE CAN GET IT .
IT 'S TERRIBLY OUT OF THE WAY ,
AND IT HASN 'T BEEN LIVED IN FOR YEARS .
WHAT WOULD WE DO WITH IT ?
WE CAN 'T DRIVE NEARLY 300 MILES
JUST FOR WEEKENDS .
WE 'LL LIVE HERE ALL THE TIME AND YOU 'LL WORK AT YOUR MUSIC .
MY POOR , LUNATIC SISTER , I HAPPEN TO HAVE A JOB .
AND WHAT A JOB- - GOING TO CONCERTS ,
AND TELLING YOUR READERS HOW BAD THE MUSIC WAS .
IT 'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH , RICK .
CHUCK IT . DOWN HERE , YOU 'D
WRITE YOUR OWN MUSIC ,
AS YOU ALWAYS SHOULD HAVE DONE , AND AS YOU 'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO .
RICK , IT ISN 'T AS IF YOU WERE EVEN A GOOD MUSIC CRITIC .
THANK YOU , VERY MUCH .
ANYWAY , I GET PAID HARD CASH .
BUT DOESN 'T THE IDEA ATTRACT YOU AT ALL ?
ATTRACT ME ?
YOU COME OUT OF HERE , YOU 'RE DANGEROUS .
DON 'T YOU KNOW HOW RARE HOUSES LIKE THIS ARE ?
I LIKE THE BANISTERS .
HOW LIZZIE WOULD LOVE THAT KITCHEN .
THAT LITTLE BEACH MUST BELONG TO IT .
IT 'S IN GOOD CONDITION TOO , NOT A SIGN OF DAMP .
- WE 'LL GET OUR FURNITURE OUT OF STORAGE . - NOW BE CALM , PAMELA .
A CHANGE LIKE THIS WOULD HAVE TO BE DISCUSSED .
OH , NONSENSE . IMPORTANT DECISIONS HAVE TO BE MADE QUICKLY .
WELL ...
MY PAPER HAS ASKED ME TO DO A SERIES- -
" LIVES OF THE GREAT MUSICIANS- - " READING TIME , TWO MINUTES .
- THERE YOU ARE , THAT WILL FEED US . - UNTIL I RUN OUT OF MUSICIANS .
HOW DO WE KNOW THIS PLACE IS FOR SALE ?
RICK , LIFE ISN 'T AS CRUEL AS THAT .
IT 'S GOT TO BE .
NOW REMEMBER , PAM , NO SIGNS OF KEENNESS .
WE 'RE JUST MILDLY INTERESTED . MILDLY .
SHH .
GOOD AFTERNOON .
Rick : WE 'D LIKE TO SEE COMMANDER BEECH IF WE MAY .
HE 'S NOT IN AT THE MOMENT .
COULD WE WAIT FOR HIM ?
WON 'T YOU COME IN ?
THERE 'S A FIRE IN THE STUDY .
I THINK I CAN CATCH MY GRANDFATHER BY TELEPHONE .
WHO SHALL I SAY WANTS TO SEE HIM ?
HE WOULDN 'T KNOW OUR NAME . IT 'S FITZGERALD .
MY SISTER PAMELA FITZGERALD AND I 'M RODERICK FITZGERALD .
HOW DO YOU DO ? I 'M STELLA MEREDITH .
WON 'T YOU SIT DOWN ?
THANK YOU .
NOT IN THAT CHAIR !
IT 'S GOT A LUMPY SEAT .
OH .
- DO YOU MIND ? - OH , NO .
- OH , DEAR . WILL THIS DO ? - THANK YOU .
WHAT AN AWFULLY UNSMOKING HOUSE .
GRANDFATHER HAD A CIGAR BLOWN STRAIGHT DOWN HIS THROAT ONCE
WHEN HE WAS ON THE FOREDECK . HE LOST HIS TASTE FOR TOBACCO .
CAN I HELP IN ANY WAY ?
WE WANTED TO TALK TO THE COMMANDER ABOUT A HOUSE HE OWNS
ON TOP OF THE CLIFF .
- WINDWARD ? - YES .
YOU SEE , WE 'VE FALLEN HEAD OVER HEELS IN LOVE WITH- -
I MEAN , IT MIGHT JUST DO FOR US .
REALLY ?
Rick : WE UNDERSTAND FROM MRS. BROWN AT THE INN IT 'S FOR SALE .
MRS. BROWN IS MISTAKEN .
I 'M SORRY YOU 'VE BEEN PUT TO THE TROUBLE OF COMING HERE .
PERHAPS IF WE COULD SPEAK TO YOUR GRANDFATHER ABOUT IT ?
IT WOULDN 'T BE THE SLIGHTEST USE .
I 'M SORRY , BUT THERE 'S REALLY NO POINT IN YOUR WAITING .
Man : STELLA , ARE YOU THERE ?
YES , GRANDFATHER .
IN HERE .
WELL , WHAT IS IT ?
SOME PEOPLE WHO CAME HERE BY MISTAKE , GRANDFATHER .
THEY 'RE JUST LEAVING .
WE HEARD THE WINDWARD HOUSE IS FOR SALE .
YES , IT IS .
WON 'T YOU SIT DOWN ? I 'LL BE WITH YOU IN A MOMENT .
Pam : THANK YOU , VERY MUCH .
GRANDFATHER , PLEASE .
I THOUGHT I MADE MYSELF QUITE CLEAR ON THIS POINT , STELLA .
YES , GRANDFATHER ...
I DON 'T UNDERSTAND YOU .
A HOUSE YOU HAVEN 'T LIVED IN SINCE YOU WERE A CHILD .
A PIECE OF PROPERTY WE CAN 'T AFFORD TO MAINTAIN .
BUT IT WAS MY MOTHER 'S HOUSE ...
I CAN 'T PUT IT INTO WORDS , IT 'S- -
NONSENSE .
GRANDFATHER , PLEASE .
I DON 'T BELIEVE MANY REPAIRS WILL BE NECESSARY .
THE ROOF IS SOUND ,
THE WALLS HAVE WITHSTOOD THE ATLANTIC GALES FOR TWO CENTURIES .
- THANK YOU . - THANK YOU .
THERE WAS A CONSIDERABLE SUM
SPENT ON THE HOUSE 20 YEARS AGO ,
WHEN I GAVE IT TO MY DAUGHTER .
Rick : I UNDERSTAND .
WELL , I 'M SORRY ,
BUT I 'M AFRAID # 1200 IS OUR ABSOLUTE LIMIT .
- IS THAT A DEFINITE OFFER ? - YES .
AND YOU WOULD PAY THE ENTIRE SUM IMMEDIATELY ?
Rick : YOU MEAN , YOU 'D SELL FOR THAT ?
YES .
I SUPPOSE YOU OUGHT TO HAVE THE PROPERTY SURVEYED BEFORE- -
OH , RICK .
THERE 'S NO NEED TO GET SUSPICIOUS .
THE HOUSE IS WORTH FAR MORE THAN THAT ,
BUT I HAVE A VERY YOUNG GRANDDAUGHTER ,
AND # 1200 IN THE BANK FOR HER
WOULD EASE MY MIND CONSIDERABLY .
Pam : WE UNDERSTAND PERFECTLY .
AND YOU WOULD NOT BE NERVOUS IN SUCH A LONELY HOUSE ?
NO , INDEED .
OR OF THE WIND AT NIGHTS ?
IT PLAYS ODD TRICKS IN OLD HOUSES .
ARE YOU TRYING TO TELL US THE HOUSE IS HAUNTED ?
NO , MISS FITZGERALD , NO HOUSE IS HAUNTED .
BUT I HAD SOME TENANTS FIVE YEARS AGO WHO COMPLAINED OF ...
DISTURBANCES .
WHAT WAS THE TROUBLE- - LADIES CARRYING THEIR HEADS UNDER THEIR ARMS ?
I DECLINED TO DISCUSS IT AND CANCELLED THE LEASE .
BUT I COULDN 'T CANCEL A SALE .
WE WOULDN 'T WANT YOU TO .
OF COURSE , ONE DOES FEEL THAT A STORY LIKE THAT SHOULD BRING THE PRICE DOWN .
I 'VE ALREADY MADE A VERY CONSIDERABLE REDUCTION , MR. FITZGERALD .
PERHAPS WE BOTH NEED TIME TO THINK THE MATTER OVER .
BUT OUR OFFER 'S DEFINITE . ISN 'T IT , RICK ?
- OH , YES , YES . - VERY WELL , THEN . I ACCEPT IT .
Beech : TITLE DEEDS AND CHECKS WILL BE EXCHANGED BY OUR SOLICITORS .
IN THE MEANTIME , I HAVE YOUR WORD
AND YOU HAVE MINE .
IT 'S WONDERFULLY SIMPLE TO BUY A HOUSE , ISN 'T IT ?
- ( barking ) - PAM , WHERE ARE YOU ?
HERE I AM . LOOK , OUR OWN ROSES .
RICK , IT 'S ALL OURS . ISN 'T IT WONDERFUL ?
HMM . YOU KNOW , IT 'S BIGGER THAN I THOUGHT .
I CAN 'T WAIT TO SEE WHAT 'S IN THAT BLUEBEARD ROOM .
PROBABLY THE HOUSEMAID 'S CUPBOARD- -
SLOPS , MOPS , DRIPPING TAPS .
I WONDER HOW SOON WE CAN GET CLEANERS AND PAINTERS IN ?
YOU 'LL GO BACK TO LONDON , OF COURSE , WHILE I STAY HERE .
WHAT , ROLLED UP IN A BLANKET LIKE A SQUAW ?
AT THE INN , IDIOT , UNTIL YOU SHIP ME THE FURNITURE .
DID THE OLD BOY TELL YOU WHY IT WAS LOCKED ?
I NEVER THOUGHT TO ASK HIM .
WELL , NOW WE KNOW .
IT 'S THE ONE UGLY ROOM IN THE HOUSE .
OH , IT 'S NOT SO BAD .
BUT THAT WINDOW , IT 'S LIKE A CUCUMBER FRAME .
THEY PUT THAT IN LATER TO MAKE A PAINTER 'S STUDIO .
EVEN THE VIEW DOESN 'T CHEER IT UP .
WHAT WILL WE DO WITH IT ?
WHAT ? MY WORKROOM , OF COURSE . IT 'S IDEAL .
PUT THE PIANO OVER THERE WITH SHELVES FOR MUSIC ,
PLENTY OF SPACE TO WALK UP AND DOWN , MANUSCRIPTS ALL OVER THE FLOOR ,
HOT PINCERS TO TEAR THE FLESH FROM PEOPLE
WHO KEEP TELLING ME LUNCHEON IS READY ,
STACKS OF CHECKS FROM MY PUBLISHERS AND- -
DO YOU THINK THIS ROOM IS DAMP ?
IT NEEDS AIRING .
IT 'S FUNNY IT SHOULD STRIKE SO COLD
IN HERE AFTER SUCH A WARM DAY .
- OH , LAW . - WHAT , RICK ?
I SUDDENLY FELT COMPLETELY FLATTENED .
DO YOU SUPPOSE I 'LL EVER BE ABLE TO WRITE ANY MUSIC HERE OR ANYWHERE ?
WHAT ON EARTH ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ?
YOU DON 'T SUPPOSE WE 'VE MADE THE MOST HOWLING MISTAKE , DO YOU ?
OH , RICK , HAVE WE ?
WHY DID THE COMMANDER SUDDENLY COME DOWN ON HIS PRICE LIKE THAT ?
THE " DISTURBANCES . " RUMORS LIKE THAT ARE DYNAMITE
IF YOU 'RE SELLING A PLACE .
PAMELA , YOU 'RE NOT GOING TO GET SCARED OF THIS GHOST BUSINESS , ARE YOU ?
OF COURSE NOT . I DON 'T BELIEVE IN THEM REALLY ,
AND I 'D BE INTERESTED , NOT SCARED . WOULDN 'T YOU ?
ME ? NO , DISTURBANCES WOULDN 'T DISTURB ME ,
NOT FOR A SINGLE SECOND .
( dog howling )
WHY , IT 'S BOBBY .
OF COURSE , IT 'S BOBBY . DON 'T GO GETTING IMAGINATIVE .
- ( dog whining ) - IT IS A FILTHY ROOM , ISN 'T IT ?
( dog barks )
Pam : WE 'RE HERE , BOBBY .
Rick : HE 'S TRYING TO TELL US ABOUT THE SQUIRREL , I EXPECT .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ? DIDN 'T HE KEEP HIS DATE WITH YOU , BOBBY ?
Pam : WHY DON 'T YOU COME UP , STUPID ?
RICK , LOOK AT THAT LAMB OF A WINDOW !
NEVER THOUGHT BOBBY WAS A KILLER AT HEART .
WHO 'S THAT STANDING OUT THERE ?
LOOKS LIKE THE OLD BOY 'S GRANDDAUGHTER .
OH , DON 'T WASTE A WAVE ON THAT ONE .
BECAUSE SHE DIDN 'T WANT US TO BUY THE HOUSE ?
OH , RICK , I THINK SHE 'D BEEN CRYING .
- HAD SHE ? - DON 'T YOU SEE ?
SHE ADORED THE HOUSE , AND WE 'VE CAST HER OUT .
ISN 'T IT AWFUL ?
STOP MAKING UP STORIES . SHE DIDN 'T LIVE HERE .
SHE JUST DOESN 'T WANT US TO . SHE 'S AN ILL-MANNERED LITTLE DOG-IN-THE-MANGER .
- ( dog barking ) - ALL RIGHT , BOBBY , ALL RIGHT .
WE 'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO THE INN AND LET YOU ORDER YOUR DINNER .
- HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN SOMETHING ? - UH-HUH .
NO .
ON SECOND THOUGHT , MY LANDING GEAR
ISN 'T WHAT IT USED TO BE .
( bell rings )
- MORNING , SIR . - MORNING .
- 20 TURRETS , PLEASE . - YES , SIR .
- ISN 'T THIS WINDWARD HOUSE ? - YES , SIR .
A FINE HOUSE TOO . GLAD TO HEAR THERE 'LL BE FOLK IN IT AGAIN .
- YOU HAVE A DOZEN OF THESE ? - LIKELY , I HAVE .
OH , MAYBE YOU 'RE THE NEW OWNER .
YES , MY SISTER AND I BOUGHT THE PLACE YESTERDAY .
WELL , WELL . I HOPE YOU 'LL BRING IT BACK TO ITSELF AGAIN .
THE LAST LOT THAT LIVED THERE WEREN 'T NO GOOD .
WENT AWAY OWING MONEY .
GOT OUT OF THEIR LEASE STARTING UGLY STORIES ABOUT THE PLACE .
SO THAT 'S HOW THE RUMORS STARTED .
THAT 'S WHAT I DO SAY .
HERE YOU ARE , SIR . NINE SEEMS TO BE ALL I HAVE .
- THAT 'S ALL RIGHT . - OF COURSE , THERE ARE OTHERS WHO SAY DIFFERENT .
- THERE ARE ? - THAT 'S ONLY NATURAL ,
AFTER THE WAY THE LADY OF WINDWARD HOUSE DIED .
GOD REST HER SOUL .
YOU MEAN THE COMMANDER 'S DAUGHTER ?
ONLY CHILD . IT CAME NEAR BREAKING THE GENTLEMAN 'S HEART .
HE 'S NEVER BEEN THE SAME SINCE .
- HOW DID SHE DIE ? - FELL OFF THE CLIFF .
- ACCIDENT ? - THAT 'S WHAT I 'D HAVE SAID .
GOOD MORNING , MR. HARDY .
A COPY OF AMATEUR GARDENING , PLEASE .
YES , MRS. COATESWORTHY . THE BEST OF LUCK TO YOU , SIR .
IF YOU HAVE A FAVORITE TOBACCO , I 'LL BE GLAD TO STOCK IT FOR YOU .
THANK YOU . GOODBYE .
THE GENT THAT JUST BOUGHT WINDWARD HOUSE .
YOU DON 'T SAY ?
- MR. FITZGERALD ? - YES ?
OH , IT 'S YOU .
MAY I SPEAK TO YOU FOR A MOMENT ?
LOOK HERE , YOUNG LADY , IF YOU WANT TO TALK ME OUT
OF WINDWARD HOUSE , YOU MIGHT JUST AS WELL SAVE YOUR BREATH .
IT ISN 'T THAT . IT 'S ABOUT ME , YESTERDAY AFTERNOON .
MY BEHAVIOR WAS INEXCUSABLE .
COME NOW , IT WASN 'T AS BAD AS ALL THAT .
THANK YOU , VERY MUCH .
YOUR GRANDFATHER MADE YOU APOLOGIZE , DIDN 'T HE ?
OH , NO , IT WAS MY MOTHER .
YOUR MOTH- -
BUT I UNDERSTOOD THAT- - I BEG YOUR PARDON ?
I KEPT LOOKING AT HER LAST NIGHT , THINKING HOW I 'D LET HER DOWN .
BUT ISN 'T YOUR MOTHER DEAD ?
YES , BUT I KNOW ALL ABOUT HER- - FROM GRANDFATHER , OF COURSE .
I WAS ONLY THREE WHEN SHE DIED .
BUT I THOUGHT YOU SAID YOU LOOKED AT HER .
HER PORTRAIT HANGS IN MY ROOM . MY FATHER PAINTED IT .
OH , THEN IT WAS HIS STUDIO .
YES , AND SHE WAS SO BEAUTIFUL .
LET 'S GO FOR A WALK .
GRANDFATHER WILL NEVER GET OVER HER DEATH .
HE 'S HATED WINDWARD EVER SINCE .
THAT 'S UNDERSTANDABLE .
BUT IT ISN 'T FAIR TO HATE A HOUSE BECAUSE SOMEONE 'S DIED THERE .
I LOVE WINDWARD BECAUSE SHE LIVED THERE
FOR THREE YEARS AND THOSE WERE MY YEARS .
AND THAT 'S WHY YOU DON 'T WANT ANYONE ELSE TO LIVE IN IT ?
THAT 'S FOOLISH , ISN 'T IT ?
NO , JUST ONE THING IS FOOLISH .
YOU 'RE LIVING SOMEBODY ELSE 'S LIFE .
HOW OLD ARE YOU , STELLA MEREDITH ?
- 20 . - YOU 'RE 20 , AND YOU 'RE PRETTY .
YOU SHOULDN 'T WASTE A SINGLE SECOND
LOOKING BACK ON THREE LITTLE YEARS .
- YOU SHOULD BE HAVING FUN . - I AM .
OH , NONSENSE . WHAT ARE YOU DOING TODAY , FOR INSTANCE ?
- OH , JUST THINGS . - FACTS , DETAILS , COME ON .
OH , DEAR .
I 'VE GOT TO MATCH SOME WOOL .
THEN I HAVE TO STOP AT THE LENDING LIBRARY
AND GET A COPY OF BLEAK HOUSE .
GRANDFATHER AND I ARE READING DICKENS .
YOU 'RE NOT GOING TO DO ANY OF THOSE THINGS . I HAVE A BETTER IDEA .
ISN 'T THIS BETTER THAN READING TO GRANDFATHER ?
OH , IT 'S WONDERFUL .
EVER GET SEASICK ?
( chuckles )
FORTUNATELY , I HAVE A STOMACH LIKE GIBRALTAR .
NOT EXTERNALLY , OF COURSE .
Stella : ARE YOU ASLEEP ?
NO , JUST WONDERING IF OUR NATIONAL CONFIDENCE
IN GIBRALTAR ISN 'T MISPLACED .
SHOULDN 'T YOU GET OUT OF THE SUN ?
NO , I 'D- - I 'D RATHER- -
REMAIN HERE .
OH , PLEASE- - THE TILLER- - PLEASE !
OH ! ( groans )
SMELLS GOOD .
THAT 'S MIMOSA . IT WAS MY MO- -
OH , I FORGOT , I 'M NOT SUPPOSED TO TALK ABOUT THAT .
- WHY ? - OUT OF THE PAST .
OH , GO AHEAD .
IT WAS MY MOTHER 'S FAVORITE PERFUME .
MY FATHER SENT ME A BOTTLE BEFORE HE DIED .
I 'VE MADE IT LAST A LONG TIME .
MIMOSA .
- EVER SEE IT GROWING ? - NO , I HAVEN 'T .
LIKE A MILLION LITTLE YELLOW BELLS , LIKE- -
( groans ) LIKE SLEIGH BELLS .
IT 'S SMOOTH AGAIN . ARE YOU FEELING BETTER ?
OH , YES .
I WAS ABOUT TO RESUME COMMAND .
BRING HER ABOUT SHARPLY . HEAD STRAIGHT FOR THE JETTY .
AVAST THE BOOM . SCUTTLE THE FUNNELS .
- OH ! - OH ! ( laughs )
LADY , PLEASE .
Boatman : I THOUGHT YOU 'D GONE OFF FOR LONDON , MR. FITZGERALD .
- JUST LEAVING NOW , BEN . - THAT 'LL BE HALF A CROWN .
- YOU DOING UP YOUR HAIR AGAIN ?
- Stella : YES .
NO , NO , NO . COME ON .
IT 'S WONDERFUL LIKE THIS . ALL LOOSE AND FREE AND WINDBLOWN .
WHAT AM I DOING ? TALKING HIGH POETRY
OR SELLING HAIRSTYLE ADVERTISING ?
- YOU LAUGH AT EVERYTHING , DON 'T YOU ? - TOO MUCH ?
OH , NO . I 'VE NEVER KNOWN ANYONE WHO LAUGHED MUCH .
SEE A LOT OF PAMELA WHILE I 'M AWAY , WILL YOU ?
- HOW LONG WILL YOU BE GONE ? - OH , ABOUT THREE WEEKS .
PERHAPS SHE 'LL LET ME HELP HER WITH CURTAINS AND THINGS .
GET HER TO TALK ABOUT ME- - IN A RESPECTFUL WAY , OF COURSE .
NONE OF THOSE ANECDOTES WHERE I 'M THE FAMILY HALFWIT .
I HOPE YOU HAVE A NICE TRIP .
- I 'LL TAKE YOU HOME FIRST . - YOU 'RE SO LATE STARTING .
- MIGHT AS WELL . - I 'D RATHER BREAK IT GENTLY
TO GRANDFATHER ABOUT OUR SAIL . IF YOU DON 'T MIND .
ALL RIGHT , GENTLY BUT FIRMLY , MIND .
- GOODBYE . - GOODBYE .
- OH , MR. FITZGERALD ! - YES ?
I ALMOST FORGOT TO SAY IT .
I 'M AWFULLY HAPPY YOU AND YOUR SISTER ARE GOING TO LIVE AT WINDWARD .
WHY , THANK YOU , STELLA MEREDITH .
WELL , HERE WE ARE .
WHAT A GRAND HOUSE , MASTER RICK .
'TIS A MANSION , SO ' TIS .
ARE YOU WORTHY OF IT ,
LIZZIE FLYNN ? THAT 'S WHAT I KEEP ASKING MYSELF .
( laughs ) 'TIS ON TOP OF THE WORLD .
- RICK ! - HELLO , PAM .
- LIZZIE ! - BABY , DARLING .
YOU DEVIL FOR BEING LATE . I WANTED YOU TO SEE
EVERYTHING WHILE IT WAS STILL DAYLIGHT .
MASTER RICK AND HIS FRIENDS AND THEIR COCKTAILS .
- WE GOT LIZZIE DRUNK . - GET ON WITH YOU , MASTER RICK .
BOBBY ! OH , BOBBY ! WHERE 'S OUR BOBBY ?
- ( whistles ) - DON 'T , RICK .
- SOMETHING HAPPEN TO HIM ? - NOTHING TRAGIC . HE JUST WANDERED AWAY .
I SUPPOSE I HAVEN 'T ENOUGH DOG APPEAL .
NO , SERIOUSLY , PAM .
HE LOATHED THE COUNTRY . YOU KNOW , NO NICE DUST BINS ,
NO SPORTING INTEREST IN FINDING A TREE .
HMM- - NEVER HEARD OF A TERRIER WALKING OUT .
AH , MISS PAMELA , I 'M DREAMING ON ME FEET .
Rick : PAM , IT 'S PERFECT . YOU 'RE PRACTICALLY STRAIGHT .
THERE 'S SOUP IN THE KITCHEN .
LOOK AT WHISKEY NOW . HE KNOWS WHERE THE FOOD IS .
- HOW DID THE FURNITURE FIT IN ? - OH , BEAUTIFULLY .
I SAW THE GRANDFATHER CLOCK . IT WAVED BOTH HANDS AT ME .
IF THE SOUP 'S BURNED , LIZZIE WILL SPANK ME .
GET ON WITH YOU , MISS .
THE SAINTS BE PRAISED . THERE 'S ME OLD ROCKER .
IT 'S BEEN 10 YEARS SINCE YOU NESTLED YOUR BUSTLE IN THAT .
( laughs )
- YOU 'VE DONE WONDERS , PAM . - THANKS .
WHAT DOES STELLA THINK OF THE CHANGES ?
- YOU MEAN STELLA MEREDITH ? - MM-HMM .
- I HAVEN 'T SET EYES ON HER . - YOU HAVEN 'T ?
I DID WRITE AND ASK HER TO TEA . GOT A REPLY FROM THE COMMANDER ,
SAYING SHE WASN 'T STRONG ENOUGH TO ACCEPT INVITATIONS .
- NOT STRONG ENOUGH ? - I EXPECT IT 'S US .
WE JUST AREN 'T NICE TO KNOW .
BUT THAT 'S NOT STELLA . SHE WAS CRAZY TO MAKE FRIENDS WITH YOU .
- SHE TOLD ME . - BUT WHERE DID YOU SEE HER ?
HMM ? OH , UH , JUST BEFORE I LEFT FOR LONDON .
WHY , YOU COLOSSAL BLUFF !
YOU WERE JUST AS SORRY FOR THAT CHILD AS I WAS .
STOP PUSHING HER INTO THE NURSERY .
SHE 'S 20 , SHE SAID SO HERSELF .
YOU LIKE HER .
I CAN 'T HELP IT .
THERE 'S KIND OF A SLEEPING BEAUTY MAGIC ABOUT THE KID .
I 'D THOUGHT I 'D DONE SOMETHING TOWARDS BREAKING THE SPELL .
SEEMS NOT .
" PRINCE CHARMLESS , " THAT 'S ME .
THAT 'LL DO FOR TONIGHT , MR. RODERICK .
IT 'S TIME FOR MISS PAMELA TO GO TO BED .
SHE LOOKS TIRED OUT .
YOU 'RE AN OLD TYRANT , LIZZIE FLYNN .
BUT YOU 'RE PERFECTLY RIGHT .
PUT THE LIGHTS OUT , RICK .
NOW , LET 'S SEE .
I THINK I TURN IT DOWN AND BLOW DOWN THE CHIMNEY .
I HAVEN 'T DONE THAT SINCE I WAS A KID .
COME ON , WHISKEY .
- ( cat meows ) - OH .
ARE YOU HAVING HIM IN YOUR ROOM ?
HE 'S USED TO IT , THE CREATURE .
GET ALONG UP NOW .
Lizzie : HAVEN 'T I CARRIED YOU ENOUGH THIS DAY ?
- GET ON UP , NOW . - I 'LL GIVE HIM A START .
WHAT IN THE NAME OF ALL THE SAINTS ?
OH , WELL , HE 'S NOT USED TO TRAVELING ,
AND STRANGE HOUSES .
HE 'LL FIND ME IF HE WANTS ME .
I 'VE NOT SLEPT WITH THE SOUND OF THE SEA
IN ME EARS SINCE I LEFT IRELAND .
WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO BACK THERE ?
I 'D SOONER SEE MYSELF DEAD .
Rick : AW , GO ON WITH YOU !
WHY , WHATEVER AILS THESE CANDLES ?
IT SEEMS TO BE A RATHER DRAFTY STAIRCASE .
RICK , I 'VE HAD A SWIM EVERY DAY FROM OUR OWN BEACH ,
AND I 'VE STARTED TO MAKE A GARDEN .
YOU LEARN THE ODDEST THINGS WHEN YOU- - WHEN YOU GARDEN .
DID YOU KNOW THERE WAS AN UPSIDE-DOWN TO SEEDS ?
NO . GOOD NIGHT .
- GOOD NIGHT , RICK . - GOOD NIGHT , MASTER RICK .
GOOD NIGHT , LIZ .
- ( knocking on door ) - COME IN !
I THOUGHT YOU WERE ASLEEP .
IT TURNS COLD IN THE NIGHT HERE SOMETIMES .
OH , THANKS .
THERE 'S SOMETHING I WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT .
DO YOU HAVE ANY NICE CAST-IRON
I CAN SWAP FOR THIS MATTRESS ?
WE 'LL GIVE YOU ANOTHER TOMORROW .
NOTHING WILL KEEP ME AWAKE TONIGHT .
WHAT PRICE OUR HOUSE ? PRETTY GOOD , HMM ?
YOU 'RE REALLY PLEASED WITH IT ?
I WAS NEVER SO HAPPY IN MY LIFE .
YOU STARTED TO SAY SOMETHING . WHAT ?
WELL , IT WAS JUST- - JUST THAT I WAS
THE ONE WHO GOT YOU TO BUY THE HOUSE- -
AND I DIDN 'T APPEAR VERY APPRECIATIVE . IS THAT IT ?
IT 'LL WAIT TILL TOMORROW .
BLESS YOU , RICK . SLEEP WELL .
YOU , TOO .
THESE ARE PRETTY GOOD APPLES .
Announcer : That concludes our broadcast for today .
Good night , everyone . Good night .
( woman sobbing )
PAM , IS THAT YOU ?
( sobbing continues )
( moaning , sighs )
- RICK . - PAMELA !
WE DON 'T WANT TO WAKE LIZZIE .
BUT , ISN 'T IT LIZZIE ?
NO , IT ISN 'T LIZZIE .
IT 'S COMING FROM DOWNSTAIRS .
IT COMES FROM EVERYWHERE , AND NOWHERE .
NOW , TAKE HOLD OF YOURSELF , PAM .
I 'M GOING DOWN AND SEARCH THE PLACE .
I 'VE SEARCHED .
THERE 'S NEVER ANYTHING THERE .
NEVER ? DO YOU MEAN YOU 'VE HEARD IT BEFORE ?
YES . IT 'S TRUE , ISN 'T IT ?
THE SOUND , I MEAN . YOU 'RE HEARING IT , TOO ?
- OF COURSE I 'M HEARING IT . - YOU SEE , I WASN 'T SURE .
- PAM ! - I THOUGHT I MIGHT BE GOING CRAZY .
WAS THAT WHY YOU DIDN 'T TELL ME ?
YES , THAT- - IT 'S YOUR HOME .
IT 'S ALL WE 'VE GOT TO LIVE IN .
( woman 's voice wails )
IT SOUNDS SO HEARTBROKEN .
NOW DON 'T GET RATTLED .
THERE 'S A LOGICAL EXPLANATION FOR THIS .
- SUCH AS ? - YOU CAN 'T EXPECT ME TO GIVE IT TO YOU OFFHAND ?
BUT IT STANDS TO REASON . DOES IT COME EVERY NIGHT ?
NO ... BUT JUST WHEN YOU BEGIN
TO THINK YOU 'VE DREAMT IT , IT COMES AGAIN .
BE CALM , PAM , BE CALM .
I 'M ALL RIGHT . IT 'LL STOP SOON NOW .
HOW DO YOU KNOW ?
IT DIES AWAY AT DAWN .
LISTEN .
( silence )
Pam : THAT 'S THE DAWN BREEZE .
WELL , THAT 'S ALL FOR TONIGHT .
THAT 'S A PITY , REALLY .
HARDLY GIVES ONE TIME TO LOOK INTO IT .
- NOW LISTEN , DEAR- - - LOOK , LET 'S TALK TOMORROW .
I 'LL DIE IF I DON 'T GET SOME SLEEP .
PAM , LEAVE YOUR DOOR OPEN IN CASE YOU 'RE NERVOUS .
ALL RIGHT , RICK .
REMEMBER , YOU HAVEN 'T A THING TO WORRY ABOUT .
THIS BUSINESS CAN BE SCIENTIFICALLY EXPLAINED .
PROBABLY A LOOSE WIRE HIDDEN AROUND THE HOUSE SOMEWHERE ,
ACTING AS AN AERIAL , PICKING UP THE SOUND
OF SOME WOMAN IN THE VILLAGE CRYING .
Pam : WAS SHE CRYING WHEN THE LAST TENANTS WERE FRIGHTENED OUT ?
WELL , MAYBE SHE HAD A SAD LIFE .
ANYWAY , I 'M HERE NOW ,
AND I 'M NOT THE LEAST RATTLED .
NOT THE LEAST LITTLE BIT IN THE WORLD .
IT 'S JUST SILLY TO BE UPSET .
( mild slam )
LAST NIGHT I HEARD A PERFECTLY APPALLING SOUND OF CRYING .
MR. FITZGERALD , WINDWARD HOUSE BELONGS TO YOU NOW .
WHY DO YOU BRING THIS MATTER TO ME ?
BECAUSE WE WANT INFORMATION .
I , FOR PRACTICAL REASONS , AND MY SISTER
BECAUSE SHE BELIEVES IT 'S A GHOST .
SHE 'D LIKE TO KNOW WHAT THE GHOST WANTS .
- WHAT UTTER BOSH . - BOSH , I AGREE .
BUT WHEN DID THE NOISES START ?
YOU INHERITED THE HOUSE , I BELIEVE ?
FROM MY GRANDMOTHER .
AND THERE WERE NO DISTURBANCES IN HER TIME ?
NONE . AND IF THERE ARE ANY NOISES NOW ,
THEY 'RE FROM PERFECTLY NATURAL CAUSES .
AN ECHO FROM A SUBTERRANEAN CAVE , PERHAPS .
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN HEARD IN YOUR GRANDMOTHER 'S DAY .
EROSION MAY HAVE CHANGED THE STRUCTURE OF THE CLIFFS .
Rick : WELL , IT 'S NOT A BAD SUGGESTION .
MAY I COME IN , GRANDFATHER ?
NO , YOU RUN ALONG TO CHURCH .
I 'LL JOIN YOU IN JUST A FEW MINUTES .
BUT I WANT TO SEE MR. FITZGERALD .
I 'M AWFULLY GLAD YOU 'RE BETTER .
BETTER ?
BUT I HAVEN 'T BEEN ILL .
STELLA MERELY SUFFERS WITH A GENERAL DELICACY .
SHE DOESN 'T ACCEPT INVITATIONS .
NEVER ?
PERHAPS I 'D BETTER FRANKLY STATE
SHE 'S NOT STRONG ENOUGH TO MAKE NEW FRIENDS .
- GRANDFATHER ? ! - RUN ALONG , MY DEAR .
WE 'RE DISCUSSING SOMETHING PRIVATE .
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE ?
NO , JUST ONE MORE QUESTION .
WAS STELLA 'S MOTHER EVER TROUBLED AT WINDWARD HOUSE ?
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN ? - DID SHE HEAR THE CRYING ?
MY DAUGHTER WAS NOT ONE TO CIRCULATE RIDICULOUS RUMORS .
IF SHE 'D HEARD THIS , SHE 'D HAVE MENTIONED IT ,
- AND SHE NEVER DID ? - CERTAINLY NOT .
THEN THE TROUBLE MUST HAVE BEGUN SINCE HER DEATH .
- DO YOU MEAN TO IMPLY- - - OH , NO , I 'M MERELY TRYING TO SET THE DATE .
I DIDN 'T MEAN THAT YOUR DAUGHTER HAUNTS- -
HOW DARE YOU SUGGEST SUCH A THING ?
REALLY , I 'M MOST DESPERATELY SORRY . PLEASE FORGIVE ME .
VERY WELL . I ACCEPT YOUR APOLOGY .
BUT PLEASE UNDERSTAND ONE THING .
YOUR PURCHASE OF THE PROPERTY
DOESN 'T ESTABLISH A SOCIAL BOND BETWEEN US .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER WITH US ?
WHY DON 'T YOU ALLOW STELLA TO SEE US ?
BECAUSE I DON 'T WANT TO .
AND I MUST ASK YOU FOR YOUR WORD
NOT TO SEND HER ANY MORE INVITATIONS .
I 'LL GIVE YOU NO SUCH UNDERTAKING .
VERY WELL , I KNOW HOW TO DEAL WITH THE MATTER .
STELLA IS NOT GOING INSIDE THAT HOUSE .
GREAT SCOTT ,
YOU BELIEVE THE PLACE IS HAUNTED .
I HOPED YOU 'D COME ALONG . I WANTED TO TALK TO YOU .
QUICK , DRIVE AROUND THE NEXT CORNER .
GET IN .
YOU HAD FOUR FRECKLES ON THE BOAT .
THEY 'VE GONE . I COULDN 'T GO TO SEE YOUR SISTER .
GRANDFATHER 'S BEEN ILL .
TURN HERE .
NOW , WHAT IS THIS ABOUT YOU NOT SEEING PAMELA ?
AT THE MERE MENTION OF ME COMING TO WINDWARD ,
GRANDFATHER ALMOST HAD AN ATTACK .
YOU FEEL YOUR MOTHER NEVER WOULD HAVE LEFT HIM ?
- NEVER . - YET SHE DID WHEN SHE MARRIED ,
- HE SEEMED TO SURVIVE VERY NICELY . - HE WAS YOUNGER THEN .
SO YOU 'RE GOING TO TURN INTO ONE OF THESE DIM LITTLE LADIES
WHO FILL HOT-WATER BOTTLES FOR ELDERLY RELATIVES ?
- GOODBYE , STELLA MEREDITH . - I 'M NOT NOW .
YOU 'RE HERE NOW .
THAT 'S PRACTICALLY THE NICEST SENTENCE THAT EVER WAS SPOKEN .
WOULD YOU AND YOUR SISTER BE IN IF I CAME TO WINDWARD TONIGHT ?
YES . SUPPER 'S AT 8 : 00 ,
BUT PLEASE COME AS EARLY AS YOU CAN .
( footsteps )
BOB DOWN . HE 'S PASSING THE END OF THE LANE .
HE 'S GONE .
HOW WILL I EVER GET TO CHURCH ?
SIT ON THE FLOOR OF THE CAR . I 'LL DRIVE YOU PAST HIM .
DRIVE TO THE SIDE GATE , PLEASE .
YES .
LIKE A LIFT , COMMANDER ?
NO , THANK YOU .
- WHAT A MOMENT . - WERE YOU SCARED ?
YES , BUT IT WAS WONDERFUL .
WELL , GOODBYE . SAY A LITTLE PRAYER FOR ME .
HOW AM I EVER GOING TO FEEL MEEK ENOUGH FOR CHURCH ?
OH , STELLA !
HERE 'S YOUR PRAYER BOOK AND PURSE .
- GOODBYE . - GOODBYE .
( congregation singing )
THANK YOU , MRS. CARLTON , COLONEL .
- Colonel : UNTIL NEXT SUNDAY . - Beech : YES .
- GOODBYE . - GOODBYE .
YOU SEEM VERY SILENT .
WHAT HAVE YOU AGAINST THE FITZGERALDS ?
WELL , THEY 'RE HARDLY OUR SORT .
I 'VE DECIDED TO MAKE FRIENDS WITH THEM .
YOU 'LL DO NO SUCH THING .
WHY DO YOU SAY THAT , GRANDFATHER ?
I DO NOT CONSIDER IT SUITABLE FOR YOU
- TO VISIT WINDWARD HOUSE . - NOT SUITABLE ?
I CAN 'T DISCUSS THE MATTER .
THEN THAT 'S ALL THE REASON I 'M GOING TO GET FROM YOU ?
IT WILL HAVE TO SUFFICE , YES .
NO , GRANDFATHER , I 'M 20 AND I 'M- -
IT 'S TIME I STOPPED LIVING SOMEBODY ELSE 'S LIFE .
I SHALL GO TO WINDWARD WHENEVER I PLEASE .
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID ?
IT ISN 'T ANY GOOD . I 'M ON STRIKE .
GO TO YOUR ROOM .
NO USE TRYING TO LOCK ME IN . THERE ISN 'T ANY KEY .
DON 'T BE IMPERTINENT .
- HELLO , ANNIE . - DINNER WILL BE LATE , MISS .
I 'M HAVING EVER SUCH TROUBLE WITH THE LAMB .
YOU 'D BETTER TELL THE COMMANDER .
YES , IT 'S VERY URGENT . WILL YOU TRY TO HURRY THE CALL ?
- ( knocking ) - THANK YOU .
I 'M TELEPHONING . CLOSE THAT DOOR .
IT 'S JUST THAT DINNER WILL BE LATE .
IT 'S THE LAMB BEING AWKWARD .
I WON 'T BE HERE FOR DINNER . TAKE SOME TO STELLA ON A TRAY .
AND CLOSE THAT DOOR !
( ringing )
MAY I SPEAK TO MISS HOLLOWAY ?
IT 'S A TRUNK CALL , MISS HOLLOWAY .
A COMMANDER BEECH .
THANK YOU .
YES , COMMANDER BEECH .
I WANT TO CONSULT YOU ABOUT STELLA , MISS HOLLOWAY .
IT 'S A MATTER OF THE UTMOST URGENCY .
I CAN BE WITH YOU LATE THIS AFTERNOON .
I CAN 'T SEE YOU UNTIL THIS EVENING ,
BUT I SHALL BE GLAD TO PUT YOU UP FOR THE NIGHT .
ISN 'T IT A LITTLE LATE TO CONSULT ME ABOUT STELLA ?
YES , YES , I KNOW THAT , BUT I BEG YOU TO HELP ME .
YOU 'RE THE ONLY HUMAN BEING IN THE WORLD TO WHOM I CAN TURN .
THE ONLY PERSON WHO WOULDN 'T THINK ME DEMENTED
BECAUSE I BELIEVE A HOUSE CAN BE FILLED WITH MALIGNITY- -
MALIGNITY DIRECTED AGAINST A CERTAIN CHILD .
THE DINING ROOM ISN 'T FINISHED YET .
HOW GLAD THIS HOUSE MUST BE TO BE LIVED IN AGAIN .
I MUST DASH BACK TO LIZZIE .
WE 'RE FIGHTING OVER HOW MUCH SHERRY YOU PUT IN A TIPSY PUDDING .
SHE WANTS TO MAKE IT DEAD DRUNK .
- DO YOU LIKE TIPSY PUDDING ? - I THINK I LIKE EVERYTHING TO EAT .
SHOW HER THE REST OF THE HOUSE , RICK , BEFORE IT 'S DARK .
YOU 'VE REALLY NEVER BEEN HERE SINCE YOU WERE THREE ?
NOT INSIDE .
BUT I WALKED HERE ONCE WHEN I WAS 10 AND PEERED IN AT THE WINDOWS .
THERE WAS A STUPENDOUS ROW .
AND THE NEXT WEEK I GOT PACKED OFF TO A SCHOOL IN BRUSSELS .
DID YOUR GRANDFATHER GIVE YOU ANY REASONS ?
REASONS ? IF I 'D EVER BEEN REASONED WITH ,
I MIGHT HAVE BEEN A BETTER CHILD .
MY OLD NURSERY 'S THROUGH THERE , ISN 'T IT ?
I SHOULD THINK SO , IT HAD NURSERY WALLPAPER .
HOW PRETTY YOUR SISTER 'S MADE IT .
WHAT IS IT ?
SOMETHING I 'VE FORGOTTEN .
WHEN I WAS LITTLE ,
I USED TO HAVE A DREAM ABOUT THIS ROOM .
YOU DID ?
I 'D BE LYING HERE ,
AND IT WOULD BE DARK AND COLD AND FRIGHTENING .
AND THEN ... A LITTLE FLAME WOULD COME- -
JUST A TINY POINT OF LIGHT SO BIG- -
AND YET SUDDENLY ...
EVERYTHING WOULD BE WARM
AND LIGHT AND PEACEFUL .
AND THEN ...
SOMEONE WOULD COME AND PUT THE FLAME OUT AND I 'D BE TERRIFIED .
PERHAPS YOUR MOTHER USED TO BRING YOU A NIGHT-LIGHT .
BUT WHO 'D TAKE IT OUT ?
MAY I SEE THE STUDIO BEFORE IT 'S DARK ?
IT 'S RATHER MESSY IN HERE . I WAS THINKING OF SKIPPING THIS .
THIS IS WHERE MY FATHER PAINTED MY MOTHER 'S PICTURE .
STRANGE TO THINK OF THEM HERE .
MY FATHER WOULD HAVE HIS EASEL TO THE LIGHT , WOULDN 'T HE ?
AND PERHAPS MY MOTHER WOULD SIT THERE IN A SOFT , WHITE DRESS .
BUT SOMETIMES , OF COURSE , HE 'D PAINT THE OTHER ONE .
- THE OTHER ONE ? - HE HAD A MODEL- - A FOREIGN GIRL .
I 'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE TO FIND OUT MUCH ABOUT HER .
PEOPLE GET AWFULLY HUSH-HUSH WHEN I ASK THEM .
BETWEEN YOU AND ME AND THE GRAND PIANO ,
I SUSPECT FATHER WAS A BIT OF A BAD HAT .
ARTISTIC TEMPERAMENT ?
VERY ARTISTIC , I 'M AFRAID .
SOMETIMES , YOU KNOW , IT 'S QUITE A COMFORT TO ME .
IN WHAT WAY ?
IF FATHER HAD BEEN AS GOOD AS MOTHER ,
THINK HOW GOOD I 'D HAVE BEEN .
IT 'S GETTING ALMOST TOO DARK TO SEE YOU PROPERLY .
WON 'T YOU PLAY SOMETHING ?
IT 'S ABOUT TIME YOU ASKED ME THAT .
( playing classical melody )
( music stops )
PLEASE GO ON .
JUST A SECOND .
- YOU MADE THAT UP ? - YES .
- BUT YOU MUST BE BRILLIANT ! - OH , DAZZLING !
PEOPLE HAVE TO WEAR SUNGLASSES .
WHAT 'S IT CALLED ?
IT 'S A SERENADE . " TO STELLA BY STARLIGHT . "
- YOU MEAN , THIS STELLA ? - MM-HMM .
IT 'S THE MOST EXCITING THING THAT 'S EVER HAPPENED TO ME .
- IS IT ? - PLEASE GO ON .
( music resumes )
YOU SEE , THIS IS THE ONLY WAY I CAN PAINT YOU .
SOME BLACK KEYS AND SOME WHITE ,
AND FINGERS THAT ARE MUCH TOO CLUMSY ,
BUT YOU 'RE IN IT , SOMEHOW .
( melancholy tone )
IT 'S GONE AWFULLY SAD . WHY HAVE YOU CHANGED IT ?
IT JUST CAME OUT THAT WAY .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
WHAT IS IT , STELLA ? YOU 'RE TREMBLING !
OH , I WAS WICKED .
HOW COULD I EVER HAVE LAUGHED IN HER HOUSE ?
BUT IT 'S MY HOUSE NOW- - PAM 'S AND MINE .
BUT SHE WAS SO YOUNG AND SHE DIED SO CRUELLY .
STELLA !
RICK , WHAT IS IT ?
I DON 'T KNOW . IT 'S THAT BLASTED ROOM !
STELLA , STOP !
STELLA !
- FOR HEAVEN 'S SAKE , STELLA . - WHAT 'S THE MATTER , RICK ?
YOU WERE GOING OVER THE EDGE .
- WAS I ? - IF I HADN 'T CAUGHT YOU .
I HADN 'T ANY SENSE OF DANGER AT ALL .
LOOK .
Stella : I THINK THIS IS WHERE MY MOTHER FELL .
BY THE DEAD TREE .
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
QUITE , THANKS- -
EXCEPT DYING OF HUNGER .
Pam : THEN YOU MUST COME AND GET SOME FOOD .
DO YOU KNOW THIS IS OUR VERY FIRST PARTY
IN THIS HOUSE ?
- IS IT ? - SHALL WE SING HER THE SONG ?
HIS INTRODUCTION TO MUSIC .
LA !
Pamela , Rick : WEE CHICKABIRDIE , TRA LA LA , LAID AN EGG ON THE VUNDYSULL
THE VUNDYSULL BEGAN TO CRACK
WEE CHICKABIRDIE , LA , LA , LA , WEE CHICKABIRDIE- -
( woman screams within )
STAY HERE .
( screaming )
LIZZIE , WHERE ARE YOU ? WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
Lizzie : MR. RODERICK ! MR. RODERICK !
WHAT IS IT , LIZZIE ? ARE YOU HURT ?
THE STUDIO DOOR .
THERE 'S SOMETHING THERE .
LOOK , LIZZIE , THERE 'S NOTHING THERE .
THERE WAS !
I SAW IT WITH ME OWN TWO EYES .
WHAT ?
IT WAS LIKE A MIST- - A CRAWLING MIST .
YOU IMAGINED IT , JUST BECAUSE YOU HEARD THE HOUSE WAS HAUNTED .
I HEARD NOTHING OF THE SORT , MR. RODERICK .
HOLY SAINTS , ARE YOU TELLIN ' ME IT IS ?
Pam : FOR HEAVENS SAKE , RICK , WHAT IS IT ?
OH , LIZZIE 'S DREAMED UP A GHOST FOR HERSELF .
COME ALONG , LIZZIE .
OH , DARLING LIZZIE .
I HAD JUST COME UPSTAIRS TO TURN DOWN THE BEDS ,
AND THERE IT STOOD BY THE STUDIO DOOR , LOOKING DOWN AT ME .
- A WOMAN , IT WAS . - FOUR STEPS BACK , IT WAS JUST A MIST .
Lizzie : ' TWAS A WOMAN , I SWEAR IT . THE GHOST OF A WOMAN !
Pam : COME SIT DOWN . YOU 'LL BE ALL RIGHT .
HAVE SOME SHERRY , LIZZIE .
JUST A DROP .
I 'LL NOT SLEEP IN THIS HOUSE ANOTHER NIGHT , MR. RODERICK .
- COME NOW , LIZZIE . - I WILL NOT ! I 'D SOONER DIE .
SHE CAN GO TO THE JESSUP FARM .
WHAT 'S HAPPENED TO STELLA ?
Pam : SHE WAS WITH ME WHEN I CAME IN .
STELLA ?
STELLA , WHERE ARE YOU ?
STELLA , ARE YOU IN THE HOUSE ?
STELLA !
PAMELA ! PAMELA !
STELLA , DARLING .
YES , RICK , WHAT 'S HAPPENED ?
- WHAT IS IT ? - SHE 'S IN A DEAD FAINT .
- THIS ROOM IS LIKE AN ICEBOX . - COLDER .
WE 'LL HAVE TO GET A DOCTOR .
THERE 'S ONE AT THE FIRST HOUSE IN THE VILLAGE .
THAT 'S THE GIRL .
WELL , WHAT KIND OF BOGEY DID YOU SEE ?
I DIDN 'T SEE ANYTHING .
FAINTED OUT OF SHEER CUSSEDNESS , HUH ?
I CAN ONLY REMEMBER THE COLD COMING .
HELLO , STELLA .
HELLO .
Doctor : YOU SUDDENLY FELT COLD ?
IT WASN 'T JUST THAT .
THE ROOM WENT COLD AND I WAS FRIGHTENED .
YES . WELL , YOU JUST FORGET ABOUT IT FOR A BIT .
MISS FITZGERALD HAS GOT SOME SOUP FOR YOU .
SEE IF YOU CAN GET HER TO TAKE SOME .
SHE 'LL DO ALL RIGHT . BUT IT 'S QUITE A NASTY CASE OF SHOCK .
THAT 'S ALL ? YOU 'RE QUITE SURE ?
- SIT DOWN . - YOU SEE , I BROUGHT HER HERE .
TAKE THAT NEAT .
CAN 'T SHE STAY THE NIGHT HERE ?
OH , YES . BUT SUPPOSE THAT SPOOK STARTS HOWLING .
- OH , YOUR SPOOK . - IT 'S JUST AN ECHO FROM A CAVE PROBABLY ,
BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE A SPOOK .
I 'D RATHER RISK IT THAN MOVE HER TONIGHT .
THERE WAS SOME RATHER QUEER BUSINESS EARLIER THIS EVENING .
THE CLIFF IS SO CLOSE AND SHE WALKED RIGHT TO THE EDGE ,
- AND IF I HADN 'T CAUGHT HER- - - WE 'LL KEEP A CLOSE WATCH .
WELL , DID SHE TAKE HER SOUP ?
EIGHT SPOONFULS , AND THEN DRIFTED OFF TO SLEEP .
SPLENDID . SHE 'LL SLEEP FOR HOURS NOW .
WE 'LL KEEP ON WATCH HERE .
YOU BETTER GO TO BED , MISS FITZGERALD . YOU 'RE LOOKING ALL IN .
I 'D RATHER WATCH WITH YOU .
- WOULD YOU LIKE SOME COFFEE ? - OH , THANKS .
OH , PAM , WHO DO YOU THINK 'S MOVED IN WITH DR. SCOTT ?
- OUR BOBBY . - NO !
I FOUND THE POOR DOG IN THE STREET ONE DAY .
HE WAS IN A PITIABLE STATE OF NERVES .
- HOW IS HE NOW ? - FINE .
BOBBY WAS THE VERY FIRST TO SEE THE GHOST .
- PAMELA BELIEVES IT . - STOP HIDING YOUR HEAD IN THE SAND .
YOU HEARD THE SOUNDS LAST NIGHT .
LIZZIE 'S BEEN HALF FRIGHTENED OUT OF HER WITS
AND STELLA 'S BEEN IN DEADLY DANGER TWICE .
EVERYONE IN THE VILLAGE KNOWS THE HOUSE IS STRANGE .
I EXPECTED SUPPORT FROM YOU .
YOU MUST TELL US EVERYTHING YOU KNOW ABOUT THE PLACE AFTER I 'VE MADE THE COFFEE .
UNFORTUNATELY , I 'M A NEWCOMER TO BIDDLECOMBE .
YOU SEE , I 'VE ONLY LIVED HERE 12 YEARS .
- ( chuckles ) - OH !
IT 'S NOT ANCIENT HISTORY TO US . PLEASE GO ON .
THE MODEL 'S NAME WAS CARMEL . SHE WAS SPANISH- -
A SPANISH GYPSY , AND A THOROUGH BAD LOT .
SO WAS MEREDITH , FROM WHAT I CAN GATHER .
- DIDN 'T MRS. MEREDITH SUSPECT ? - SHE MUST HAVE , THE THING WAS AN OPEN SCANDAL .
THE GIRL AND HE 'D HAVE BEEN STONED OUT OF THE VILLAGE
IF IT HADN 'T BEEN FOR MARY MEREDITH . SHE WAS VERY MUCH ADMIRED .
I SUPPOSE SHE JUST ACCEPTED THE SITUATION .
AND SHE 'S STILL SOBBING HER HEART OUT ABOUT IT .
- WHERE 'S CARMEL NOW ? - DEAD . SHE DIED IN THIS VERY HOUSE ,
A WEEK AFTER MARY FELL FROM THE CLIFF TRYING TO SAVE HER FROM SUICIDE .
- IRONIC , WASN 'T IT ? - IS IT KNOWN WHY THE GIRL TRIED TO KILL HERSELF ?
MEREDITH 'S SAID TO HAVE TIRED OF HER .
THINK OF IT- - THOSE TWO WOMEN STRUGGLING ON THE CLIFF .
I WONDER IF MARY 'S DEATH COULD HAVE BEEN MURDER ?
IT 'S BEEN HINTED AT , ALL RIGHT .
THE WHOLE STORY WAS DUG UP AND EMBROIDERED
WHEN STELLA 'S FATHER DIED .
- WHEN WAS THAT ? - THREE YEARS AGO , ABROAD .
HE NEVER CAME BACK TO WINDWARD .
ALL OF THEM DEAD WITH THEIR SECRETS .
ONE OF THEM 'S NOT QUITE DEAD ENOUGH FOR ME .
DON 'T SAY THAT ABOUT THE POOR SOUL .
I TELL YOU , RICK , IF A SPIRIT COMES BACK ,
IT 'S FOR SOME PARTICULAR PURPOSE .
THAT 'S MY SISTER 'S SPECIAL CROTCHET .
WE 'VE GOT TO FIND OUT WHAT IT IS .
I WISH I KNEW SOME MORE , BUT I 'M AFRAID I DON 'T .
WHAT TIME IS YOUR WAILING LADY DUE ?
ABOUT DAWN .
WELL , WE OUGHT TO KNOW EACH OTHER PRETTY WELL BY THEN .
21 HAND .
I 'M OUT .
- IS IT MY DEAL ? - IT WAS TWO HOURS AGO .
( yawns )
5 : 30 .
YES , MOANING MARTHA SEEMS TO HAVE MISSED HER CUE .
RICK , HAVE YOU BROUGHT SOME MORE FLOWERS IN ?
NO . WHY ?
DON 'T YOU NOTICE THE SCENT ? IT 'S OVERPOWERING .
Dr. Scott : EXTRAORDINARY . HELIOTROPE , ISN 'T IT ?
NO .
NO , IT 'S MIMOSA .
THERE 'S A LIGHT !
WHERE DID THAT COME FROM ?
IT 'S LIKE A NIGHT-LIGHT .
SHE 'S GONE !
RICK , THE WINDOW !
- Stella : WHAT IS IT ? - Pam : WHERE ARE YOU , STELLA ?
DON 'T BE AFRAID , STELLA .
AFRAID ?
WELL , WE WERE A LITTLE .
I WANTED TO SEE THE DAWN- - WITH HER .
HER ?
DON 'T YOU KNOW WHO IT IS IN YOUR HOUSE ?
- IT 'S MY MOTHER . - YOU SAW HER ?
I DIDN 'T SEE HER ,
BUT WHEN I WOKE , SHE WAS HERE IN THE ROOM .
IT WAS FULL OF HER SCENT .
I COULD FEEL HER PRESENCE EVERYWHERE .
AND THERE WAS SOMETHING ELSE ...
SOMETHING I 'VE NEVER KNOWN IN MY WHOLE LIFE .
Rick : WHAT ?
THE KNOWLEDGE THAT ...
SOMEONE LOVED ME VERY DEARLY .
NOW , COME ON , YOUNG STELLA , I 'LL TAKE YOU HOME .
BUT I DON 'T WANT TO GO .
SORRY , BUT I 'VE GOT TO GET SOME SLEEP , YOU KNOW .
BUT I CAN COME BACK ?
NO .
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ? YOU COULDN 'T WANT TO KEEP ME AWAY FROM HER .
STELLA , REMEMBER HOW ILL YOU WERE LAST NIGHT ?
BUT THAT WAS NOTHING TO DO WITH HER .
I WAS JUST FRIGHTENED AFTER WHAT LIZZIE SAID .
I TELL YOU , MY MOTHER WOULD NEVER HURT ME .
I SHAN 'T BE AFRAID AGAIN , PLEASE .
I 'M SORRY .
IT 'S JUST THAT MY KNEES ARE WOBBLY .
COME ALONG . DR. SCOTT WILL DRIVE YOU HOME .
( car motor starts )
I WONDER WHAT I 'VE DONE TO HER , PAMELA ,
BRINGING HER HERE .
DON 'T BLAME YOURSELF .
BUT THAT LOOK IN HER EYES- -
THAT TERRIBLE HAPPINESS .
OH !
WAIT A MINUTE , RICK . PERHAPS SHE 'S NEARER RIGHT THAN WE ARE .
- SHE 'S WHAT ? - PERHAPS SHE 'S RIGHT IN BEING HAPPY .
SUPPOSING MARY MEREDITH 'S SPIRIT HAD BEEN SEARCHING FOR STELLA ,
AND NOW THAT IT 'S FOUND HER , IT 'S FOUND PEACE .
SUPPOSE WE HAVEN 'T A GHOST ANYMORE .
WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
TO THE STUDIO .
HOW HAS IT ALWAYS SHOWN ITSELF IN THE PAST ?
SOBBING SOUNDS DOWNSTAIRS
AND COLD AND DEPRESSION IN THE STUDIO .
THERE WASN 'T ANY SOBBING TONIGHT ,
ONLY WARMTH AND FRAGRANCE .
- BUT WHY THE STUDIO ? - I 'LL KNOW IN THERE .
I 'LL KNOW WHETHER IT 'S A DECENT HUMAN ROOM .
WON 'T YOU ?
IT MAY NOT BE QUITE SO COLD , REALLY .
STOP IT , PAM . IT 'S CLAMMY AND ROTTEN .
WHATEVER IT IS , IT 'S IN HERE WITH US .
LET 'S GET OUT .
( distant weeping )
( moaning )
MARY MEREDITH , PLEASE .
PLEASE ! WE 'RE SORRY YOU HAD TO SUFFER .
- ( weeping continues ) - ISN 'T THAT ENOUGH ?
WHAT MORE DO YOU WANT ?
YOU WERE RIGHT ABOUT ONE THING , PAM .
WE HAVEN 'T A GHOST ANYMORE- - WE 'VE GOT TWO OF THEM !
IS COMMANDER BEECH AT HOME ?
HE WON 'T BE BACK UNTIL THIS EVENING , SIR .
IT 'S STELLA THAT I REALLY WANT TO SEE .
- WON 'T YOU COME IN , SIR ? I 'LL TELL HER . - THANK YOU .
MISS STELLA 'S IN HER ROOM , SIR . I 'LL- -
- RICK . - STELLA .
- I KNEW YOU COULDN 'T MEAN IT . - MEAN WHAT ?
HAVEN 'T YOU COME TO TAKE ME TO WINDWARD ?
NO , STELLA .
YOU MUSTN 'T GO THERE AGAIN , EVER .
LISTEN , DARLING ,
I 'VE THOUGHT THIS THING OUT ,
AND YOU MUST GO AWAY FROM HERE .
- GO AWAY ? - YES , FOREVER .
YOU WOULDN 'T CARE ?
NOT IN THE LEAST , BECAUSE I 'LL BE COMING WITH YOU .
IT WON 'T BE LUXURY- - JUST THE SMALLEST LONDON FLAT- -
BUT IT WILL BE OURS . AND NO UNSEEN , UNINVITED GUESTS .
- AND WINDWARD ? - WE 'LL TEAR IT DOWN AND FORGET IT .
AND MY MOTHER ?
BUT STELLA , YOU 'RE TALKING OF A DREAM AND A MEMORY .
I 'M TALKING ABOUT MY MOTHER . SHE 'S BEEN WAITING FOR ME .
IN SOME QUEER SORT OF WAY ,
I ALWAYS KNEW IT .
BUT WHAT ABOUT ME ? I WAS UNDER THE IMPRESSION THAT YOU CARED FOR ME .
THIS HASN 'T ANYTHING TO DO WITH YOU .
YOU TALK ABOUT DESTROYING THAT HOUSE- - YOU 'D BE TEARING ME APART .
STOP IT , STELLA .
DO YOU CARE FOR ME , OR DON 'T YOU ?
I CAN 'T THINK ABOUT YOU , NOT WHILE SHE 'S OUT THERE .
TAKE ME THERE , RICK .
BUT THIS IS HORRIBLE , UNHEALTHY STUFF .
PUT IT OUT OF YOUR MIND , STELLA .
TURN YOUR BACK ON THE PAST AND RUN , RUN HARD !
I 'LL GO THERE SOMEHOW .
YOU WON 'T , I PROMISE YOU .
I HATE YOU FOR THAT .
STELLA !
YOU SHAN 'T MAKE ME FORGET HER ! YOU SHAN 'T !
OH !
THAT 'S ENOUGH , BOBBY , THAT 'S ENOUGH !
YOU 'LL GET LIPSTICK POISONING .
HE 'S GOT A PASSION FOR HARD-BOILED EGGS .
- DID YOU KNOW ? - AND TURNIP TOPS .
I DON 'T THINK HE HAS ANY IDEA HE 'S A DOG . NOT REALLY .
OF COURSE , HE THINKS HE HAS A RATHER ODD FIGURE FOR A MAN .
I DIDN 'T QUESTION HIM VERY CLOSELY ABOUT WHERE HE BELONGED .
YOU SEE , I WAS AFRAID I MIGHT FIND OUT .
- I 'M SORRY NOW . - YOU 'RE SORRY ?
YES . I SHOULD HAVE MET YOU SOONER .
Rick : ARE YOU THERE , SCOTT ?
IN HERE .
Pam : DID YOU SEE STELLA ?
YES , I DID . SCOTT , YOU 'VE GOT TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THAT GIRL .
- SHE 'S ON THE EDGE OF A NERVOUS COLLAPSE . - YOU 'RE TELLING ME ?
THIS IS HARDLY A CASE FOR A COUNTRY DOCTOR , YOU KNOW .
Pam : WHEN DOES THE COMMANDER GET BACK ?
LAST TRAIN TONIGHT . HEAVEN HELP YOUNG STELLA THEN .
CAN 'T YOU CONVINCE HER THAT HER MOTHER
WOULDN 'T WANT HER TO GO NEAR THAT BLASTED HOUSE ?
NOT I. SHE 'S BEEN LISTENING FOR A VOICE
THAT 'S BEEN STILL FOR 17 YEARS .
I CAN GIVE HER A SEDATIVE .
WHY DON 'T WE TRY TO GET A MESSAGE FROM MARY MEREDITH ?
- DO WHAT ? - WE COULD HOLD A SEANCE .
YOU 'RE NOT SERIOUS !
THAT 'S HOW THE DEAD ARE SUPPOSED TO COMMUNICATE WITH THE LIVING .
Rick : ACCORDING TO THE IDIOT FRINGE .
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT TO SAY THAT .
MANY INTELLIGENT PEOPLE BELIEVE IN SPIRITUALISM .
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN TO A SEANCE ?
- I HAVE . - SHADED LIGHTS , THE ALPHABET LAID OUT ON A TABLE ,
AN UPSIDE-DOWN WINE GLASS , MESSAGES FROM SOMEBODY 'S UNCLE OSWALD ,
HOW TO FIND A MISLAID TOOTHBRUSH- - OH !
OH , STOP SCOFFING , RICK . NOT ALL SEANCES ARE FAKED .
ALL RIGHT , WE 'LL HAVE A SEANCE .
IT SHOULDN 'T BE DIFFICULT TO MOVE A WINE GLASS AROUND AND SAY IT 'S MARY MEREDITH .
- WHAT DO YOU THINK , SCOTT ? - LEAVE ME OUT OF THIS .
I WON 'T LET YOU CHEAT STELLA .
BUT WHAT DO YOU EXPECT MARY MEREDITH TO TELL HER ?
ENTRUST YOUR LIFE TO A TALL , DARK MAN , EXCRUCIATINGLY HANDSOME ?
CRIKEY , NO ! I WANT TO SET STELLA 'S MIND AT REST .
- SHE 'S ABOUT TORN IN TWO . - WELL , I WILL SAY THIS- -
UNLESS THE CONFLICT INSIDE HER IS STOPPED ,
IT MAY EVEN AFFECT HER REASON .
WELL , HERE 'S A MESSAGE THAT MIGHT DO IT- -
STELLA , THIS IS YOUR MOTHER .
SINCE I 'VE FOUND YOU , I 'VE FOUND PEACE .
STAY AWAY FROM WINDWARD HOUSE .
- BUT STELLA WOULD HAVE TO BE AT THE SEANCE . - NATURALLY .
IT 'LL HAVE TO BE AT WINDWARD , AND IT 'S DANGEROUS FOR HER TO BE THERE .
- BUT WE 'D BE WITH HER ALL THE TIME . - IT MAY BE WORTH A TRY .
THE IMPORTANT THING IS THAT WE SHOULD ALL BELIEVE- -
ISN 'T IT , DR. SCOTT ?
SO I UNDERSTAND . WHAT NOW ?
EVERYBODY PUTS A FINGER ON THE GLASS .
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD ASK SOME QUESTIONS , STELLA .
IS ANYBODY HERE ?
Stella : ARE YOU MY MOTHER ?
YOU DON 'T WANT ME TO STAY AWAY FROM WINDWARD , DO YOU , MOTHER ?
I KNEW IT , MOTHER .
I WANT TO BE NEAR YOU , TOO .
IS THAT WHY YOU STAY HERE , JUST TO BE NEAR ME ?
BUT YOU 'RE HOLDING IT , RICK .
AND YOU , DR. SCOTT , HOLDING IT HARD .
TAKE YOUR FINGERS OFF .
IS THAT YOUR REASON , DARLING ,
JUST TO BE NEAR ME ?
BUT WHAT ELSE ?
I ...
G ...
U ...
A ...
" I GUARD . "
YOU MEAN , YOU GUARD ME , FROM SOME DANGER ?
BUT WHAT ?
C ...
A ...
R ... M ...
Rick , Pam : " CARMEL " !
( glass breaks )
- THAT 'S ENOUGH . - IT IS , INDEED .
LET 'S GO INTO THE OTHER ROOM .
STELLA , WHAT IS IT ? !
- ARE YOU ILL , STELLA ? - QUIET . LEAVE HER ALONE .
OIGNAN . OIGNAN !
- STOP HER , SCOTT . - SHH . SHE 'S IN A TRANCE .
I SAW THIS HAPPEN ONCE BEFORE AT A SEANCE . I THOUGHT IT WAS A FAKE .
- BUT THIS ISN 'T . - I KNOW , AND IT 'S DANGEROUS .
- MAY I ASK HER SOME QUESTIONS ? - NO , NO !
IT MAY BE BEST TO TRY AND REACH HER MIND .
NOW KEEP YOUR VOICE QUIET AND REASSURING .
ARE YOU MARY MEREDITH , STELLA 'S MOTHER ?
EYA NO 'E . EYA NO 'E .
NO LE CREAN NA !
NO LE PONGAN OIDOS QUE ESTA MINTIENDO .
DON 'T ASK HER ANYMORE !
( doorbell jingling )
Pam : THAT 'S THE DOORBELL . SHALL I ANSWER IT ?
LIZZIE 'S AT THE JESSUPS .
NO , DON 'T MOVE UNTIL SHE 'S OVER THE WORST OF THIS .
So ladrona ! Ladrona de mi cariño !
- THAT 'S SPANISH , ISN 'T IT , SCOTT ? - I DON 'T KNOW .
RICK , THE MIMOSA SCENT !
THE ROOM 'S FULL OF IT !
MARY MEREDITH 'S IN HERE , TOO !
( gasps )
( doorbell jingles )
THE COLD .
IT 'S NEVER BEEN COLD IN HERE .
CANDLES ! LOOK AT THE CANDLES !
( Stella sobbing )
( doorbell jingles )
- Pam : I 'D BETTER ANSWER IT . - ALL RIGHT .
STOP , PAMELA !
DON 'T GO NEAR THAT DOOR .
IT 'S COMING TOWARD US !
( glass breaks )
WHAT IN THUNDER IS THIS ? !
STELLA ! STELLA , IT 'S ALL RIGHT NOW .
- WE MUST GET HER OUT . - Scott : YES .
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN DOING TO THE CHILD ?
WHAT 'S THE MEANING OF THIS , DR. SCOTT ?
I CAN 'T EXPLAIN NOW , COMMANDER .
THIS IS INCREDIBLE BEHAVIOR !
QUIETLY , STELLA , QUIETLY . THERE 'S NOTHING TO BE FRIGHTENED OF .
- CONTROL YOURSELF , CHILD ! - DON 'T SPEAK TO HER LIKE THAT !
YOU 'RE RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS- - YOU AND YOUR CRIMINAL MEDDLING .
I AM AND SO ARE YOU . WHY DIDN 'T YOU TELL US THE TRUTH ABOUT THE HOUSE ?
- I WARNED YOU . - ONLY OF IDLE GOSSIP !
PERHAPS YOU 'D LIKE YOUR MONEY BACK .
YOU SHALL HAVE IT- - THE ENTIRE PURCHASE PRICE .
NO , THANK YOU , COMMANDER . I KNOW THIS NOW- -
STELLA WILL NEVER BE WELL UNTIL THIS HOUSE IS CURED .
AND SOMEHOW , WE 'RE GOING TO CURE IT !
DR. SCOTT , HAVE THE GOODNESS TO DRIVE US HOME .
THERE . NOW YOU 'LL SLEEP ALL RIGHT .
I 'LL BE HERE EARLY IN THE MORNING .
STELLA IS NO LONGER YOUR PATIENT , NOR AM I.
BUT SOMEONE MUST LOOK AFTER HER .
THAT IS NOT YOUR CONCERN , DR. SCOTT .
I SHALL BE AT YOUR DISPOSAL AT ANY HOUR , REMEMBER .
THANK YOU .
EVERYTHING WILL BE ALL RIGHT .
WON 'T YOU COME IN , MISS HOLLOWAY ?
- IS SHE ASLEEP ? - NOT YET .
HELLO , STELLA .
MISS HOLLOWAY .
GO TO SLEEP , STELLA .
DR. SCOTT TELLS ME SHE WENT INTO A TRANCE TONIGHT- -
SPOKE SOME WORDS THEY THOUGHT WERE SPANISH .
HOW DID SHE HAPPEN TO BE AT WINDWARD ?
THE PEOPLE WHO BOUGHT THE PLACE ARE SEARCHING INTO ITS PAST .
ARE THEY INDEED !
CAN YOU MAKE THE CHILD WELL AGAIN ?
I HOPE SO . IT WON 'T BE A SHORT PROCESS .
SHE 'S FAR MORE ILL THAN YOU IMAGINE .
SHE WON 'T WANT TO GO WITH YOU .
SHE 'S NEVER OUTGROWN HER CHILDISH FEAR OF YOU .
I COULD HAVE CURED IT YEARS AGO IF YOU 'D LET ME HAVE HER ,
AS MARY WOULD HAVE WISHED ME TO .
HER PLACE WAS IN MARY 'S HOME . I 'VE TAUGHT HER TO BE LIKE MARY IN EVERY WAY .
HOW CAN YOU SAY SUCH A THING ? !
SHE 'S NOT SO BEAUTIFUL , OF COURSE .
Miss Holloway : MARY WAS A GODDESS !
HER SKIN WAS RADIANT , AND THAT BRIGHT , BRIGHT HAIR !
HOW THIS ROOM BRINGS HER BACK TO ME .
THE NIGHTS WE SAT TALKING IN FRONT OF THAT FIREPLACE ,
PLANNING OUR WHOLE LIVES .
IT WASN 'T FLIRTATIONS AND DRESSES WE TALKED ABOUT .
WE WERE NO SILLY , GIGGLING GIRLS .
WE INTENDED TO CONQUER LIFE .
YOU AT LEAST DID .
WILL YOU TRY TO TAKE MARY 'S PLACE WITH HER NOW ?
I 'LL DO MY BEST .
Miss Holloway : SHE 'S ASLEEP .
IF YOU 'LL CALL MY CHAUFFEUR , HE 'LL CARRY HER DOWNSTAIRS .
IT WILL BE BETTER FOR HER TO WAKE AT MY PLACE .
I 'M DEEPLY GRATEFUL TO YOU .
SO THEY 'RE SEARCHING INTO THE PAST ?
THEY SHAN 'T EVER FIND OUT , MY DARLING- -
I PROMISE YOU !
Rick : ELIZABETH FLYNN , WHERE ARE YOU ?
I 'M HERE , MR. RODERICK .
AND WILL YOU PLEASE COME HERE AT ONCE ?
DON 'T WE GET ANY BREAKFAST ? WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
OH- - OH , THAT !
THAT HAPPENED LAST NIGHT .
I AM NOT TALKING ABOUT THAT .
I AM TALKING ABOUT THIS .
THE ANAGRAM LETTERS ? YES , YES .
ANAGRAMS , IS IT ?
DON 'T YOU TRY TO BLUFF ME , MR. RODERICK .
'TIS A HEATHEN DEVICE TO CALL DEVILS OUT OF HELL .
STOP LOOKING AT ME AS THOUGH YOU WERE GOING TO TAKE AWAY MY BICYCLE .
I WILL NOT STAY IN A HOUSE WHERE IT GOES ON ,
AND THAT IS AN ULTIMATO !
OH , COME NOW , LIZZIE .
FROM NOW ON WE 'RE THROUGH WITH ALL THIS RUBBISH .
- WE 'RE GOING AFTER THE FACTS . - Pam : WHAT FACTS ?
THE FACTS ABOUT THIS BLASTED HAUNTING .
RICK , WHY BURDEN LIZZIE WITH THIS ?
WHISHT NOW , MISS PAM . WHERE WILL WE START , MR. RICK ?
I DON 'T KNOW . EVERYBODY SEEMS TO BE DEAD .
- THE TRAINED NURSE ISN 'T . - WHAT TRAINED NURSE ?
SHE WAS HERE WHEN IT HAPPENED- - THE FRIEND OF THE POOR LADY THAT WENT OVER THE CLIFF .
WHERE DID YOU HEAR ALL THIS ?
NOW WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE WE TALK OF AT THE JESSUPS ?
IT WAS THE TRAINED NURSE THAT SHOUTED DOWN
TO MR. JESSUP ON THE SHORE .
WAS JESSUP IN ON THE TRAGEDY ?
HE WAS AFTER SOME LOST SHEEP .
THE TIDE WAS OUT , SO HE WENT DOWN .
AND AS HE PASSED UNDER THE DEAD TREE ,
- HE HEARD A SCREAM . - MRS. MEREDITH ?
NO , ' TWAS THE SCREAM OF A TERRIFIED CHILD .
AND AS HE RAN TOWARDS IT ,
THE POOR LADY CAME CRASHING DOWN .
'TWAS THEN THAT THE NURSE CALLED .
LIZZIE FLYNN , YOU 'RE A GOLD MINE .
NOW IF WE COULD ONLY GET THE NAME OF THIS NURSE .
SURE , THAT 'S EASY . WAIT NOW .
- MR. JESSUP ! - YES , MRS. FLYNN ?
WHAT WAS THE NAME OF MRS. MEREDITH 'S
TRAINED NURSE- -
THE ONE THAT GOT SO FAMOUS AND GRAND ?
- MISS HOLLOWAY . - AH !
MISS HOLLOWAY .
SHE 'S A BIG , FINE PLACE OF HER OWN NOW- -
A HOSPITAL , LIKE . 'TIS ON BODMIN MOOR .
SHE CALLS IT " THE MARY MEREDITH RETREAT . "
- MR. AND MISS FITZGERALD ? - Rick : YES .
- WON 'T YOU COME IN ? - THANK YOU .
WAIT IN THERE , PLEASE .
I WILL ANNOUNCE YOU TO MISS HOLLOWAY .
THE PLACE IS QUITE STUNNING , ISN 'T IT ?
WHY ARE YOU WHISPERING ?
WHY ARE YOU ?
OOH !
A GENTLEMAN !
HOW VERY UNUSUAL .
- GOOD AFTERNOON . - OH , DEAR ME ...
YES . GOOD AFTERNOON .
GOOD AFTERNOON .
ARE YOU BY ANY CHANCE WAITING TO SEE MISS HOLLOWAY ?
YES , WE HAVE AN APPOINTMENT .
WHAT LUCKY PEOPLE .
AND WHAT LUCK FOR ME , TOO ,
BECAUSE I 'M SURE YOU WON 'T MIND- -
- BUT PERHAPS YOU WILL . - IS THERE SOMETHING WE CAN DO ?
OH , IF YOU 'D BE SO VERY KIND .
YOU SEE ,
THIS ISN 'T MY DAY FOR AN INTERVIEW ,
AND I WANT HER TO HAVE THESE .
WHAT ARE THEY- - BIRD 'S EGGS ?
OOH !
BUT THAT 'S VERY FUNNY ,
BECAUSE YOU SEE , I 'M MISS BIRD .
THEY 'RE JUST LITTLE STONES ,
BECAUSE SHE LIKES SIMPLE THINGS ,
AND SHE HAS SO MANY FLOWERS .
THERE ISN 'T MUCH ELSE ONE CAN FIND .
WELL , I 'LL GIVE THEM TO HER .
THANK YOU .
AND NOW , I ...
THINK I 'LL JUST GO OUT FOR A LITTLE WALK .
GO BACK TO YOUR WORK AT ONCE , MISS BIRD !
DON 'T FORGET !
Woman : WILL YOU COME THIS WAY , PLEASE ?
- SHALL I TAKE THEM ? - NO , I 'LL DELIVER THEM .
AS YOU WISH .
- ( knocking ) - Miss Holloway : COME IN .
- HOW DO YOU DO ? - HOW DO YOU DO ?
THIS IS SO KIND OF YOU .
I WAS ASKED TO GIVE YOU THESE BY A MISS BIRD , I BELIEVE .
POOR MISS BIRD . OUR SADDEST CASE .
THEY 'RE REALLY VERY FINE STONES , AREN 'T THEY ?
I MUST REMEMBER TO THANK HER FOR THEM .
SHE COMES TO ME ONCE A WEEK FOR A LITTLE CHAT .
- WON 'T YOU SIT DOWN ? - THANK YOU .
MISS HOLLOWAY , FORGIVE OUR IGNORANCE , BUT WE KNOW SO VERY LITTLE OF YOUR WORK .
IS IT WITH MENTAL PATIENTS ?
NOT PATIENTS , MISS FITZGERALD , JUST GUESTS .
IN A WAY THIS IS LIKE A HOTEL- -
WHERE THERE ARE BEAUTIFUL THINGS TO LOOK AT , MUSIC TO HEAR ,
AND A LITTLE SYMPATHY .
BUT DON 'T LET 'S TALK ABOUT ME .
YOU TOLD ME ON THE TELEPHONE ABOUT DISTURBANCES AT WINDWARD .
HOW CAN I HELP YOU ?
WE THOUGHT , PERHAPS , YOU COULD TELL US
WHAT MARY AND CARMEL WERE REALLY LIKE .
THEY WERE EXTRAORDINARY WOMEN , BOTH OF THEM .
MARY MEREDITH WAS THE FINEST HUMAN BEING I EVEN KNEW .
- Rick : IS THAT SHE ? - YES .
- Pam : AND CARMEL ? - SHE WAS EXCEPTIONAL , TOO .
I NEVER SAW SUCH INTENSITY OF EVIL .
SHE WAS A SPANISH GYPSY- - CRAFTY , CRUEL !
I 'M SORRY .
WHY DID MRS. MEREDITH PUT UP WITH IT ?
SHE THOUGHT MEREDITH SHOULD BE THE ONE TO END THE WRETCHED AFFAIR .
- AND DID HE ? - OH , YES , IN TIME .
SHE AND MEREDITH TOOK THE GIRL TO PARIS ,
FOUND A POSITION FOR HER , LEFT HER WELL SUPPLIED WITH MONEY .
THEN THEY CAME BACK HERE WITH THEIR BABY .
FOR A TIME IT SEEMED AS IF
THERE WAS SOME POSSIBILITY OF HAPPINESS .
- AND THEN ? - CARMEL CAME BACK .
SHE STILL WANTED MARY 'S HUSBAND . YOU KNOW HOW IT ENDED .
A NEIGHBOR OF OURS SPOKE OF SOMETHING WE CAN 'T QUITE UNDERSTAND .
HE MENTIONS A CHILD CRYING ON THE CLIFF THAT NIGHT .
A TERRIFIED CHILD .
OH .
THAT 'S A PART OF THE STORY SO ...
UGLY I 'VE NEVER MENTIONED IT BEFORE .
WE 'RE SORRY TO DISTRESS YOU .
THAT NIGHT , THE GIRL CARMEL
HAD BEEN TOLD SHE MUST LEAVE WINDWARD .
IF SHE COULD HAVE KILLED BOTH MARY AND HER HUSBAND SHE WOULD HAVE DONE SO .
A BETTER PLAN FLASHED INTO HER WICKED LITTLE BRAIN .
SHE WENT INTO THE NURSERY ,
PICKED UP THEIR BABY , AND RACED TO THE CLIFF .
- Pam : GOOD HEAVENS ! - MARY WAS AFTER IT IN A SECOND ,
MEREDITH AND I CLOSE BEHIND .
CARMEL REACHED THE CLIFF BY THE DEAD TREE .
FOR A MOMENT , I SAW THEM STRUGGLING ,
THEN CARMEL RAISED HER ARM ... AND STRUCK MARY DOWN .
THEN IT WAS MURDER ?
THE WILL TO KILL HAD ALWAYS BEEN THERE , I THINK .
DIRECTED AGAINST STELLA .
CAN THAT BE WHAT SURVIVES ?
MAYBE THAT ACCOUNTS FOR STELLA 'S QUEER BUSINESS ON THE CLIFF .
WHAT WAS THAT ?
SOMETHING IN THAT HOUSE DROVE HER OUT TOWARD THE EDGE ,
AND IF I HADN 'T CAUGHT HER , SHE 'D HAVE GONE OVER .
WOULD SHE INDEED ?
HOW VERY CURIOUS .
PLEASE FINISH YOUR STORY .
IT WAS FINISHED .
EVERYTHING WAS FINISHED .
MEREDITH WENT DOWN THE CLIFF .
MARY WAS DEAD WHEN HE REACHED HER .
Rick : AND CARMEL ?
SHE RAN OUT INTO THE STORM .
NEXT MORNING SHE CRAWLED BACK IN THE EARLY STAGES OF PNEUMONIA .
I FOUGHT FOR CARMEL 'S LIFE , DAY AND NIGHT ,
HATING HER ALL THE TIME !
Pam : HOW AWFUL FOR YOU .
I 'M SORRY , I DISCIPLINE OTHERS ...
I CAN 'T DISCIPLINE MYSELF .
THERE .
HAVE I TOLD YOU EVERYTHING YOU WANT TO KNOW ?
ALL EXCEPT ONE THING .
THAT LAST NIGHT , WHO TOLD CARMEL SHE MUST GO ?
WHY , MARY- -
I SHOULD SAY MEREDITH .
IT 'S THE ONE DECENT THING I EVER KNEW HIM TO DO .
THIS IS ALL EXTREMELY- -
I 'M SORRY .
MAY I OFFER YOU TEA ?
THANK YOU , BUT WE MUST GET BACK BEFORE OUR MAID LEAVES .
SHE WON 'T STAY AT WINDWARD AFTER DARK .
I 'M AFRAID I HAVEN 'T BEEN MUCH HELP WITH YOUR PROBLEM .
THANK YOU ANYWAY , AND GOODBYE .
- GOODBYE . - GOODBYE .
GOOD AFTERNOON , MY DEAR .
DO YOU WANT TO SEE ME ?
I 'VE BEEN ASKING FOR YOU ALL DAY .
I 'M BEING TREATED AS THOUGH I WERE INSANE .
HAS ANYONE USED THAT WORD ?
I 'VE TOLD THEM A THOUSAND TIMES- -
IT ISN 'T A QUESTION OF A WORD .
MY DOOR 'S KEPT LOCKED AND THERE 'S A QUEER LOOK IN THEIR EYES .
OH . YOU FEEL PERSECUTED .
NO .
ABOUT THE CLIFF AT WINDWARD , STELLA- -
WHAT DID YOU FEEL AS YOU RAN TOWARD IT ?
I DIDN 'T FEEL ANYTHING .
I WAS SAD IN THE HOUSE- -
WAS IT AS THOUGH SOME WILL WERE DIRECTING YOU ,
A WILL STRONGER THAN YOURS ?
THE SEA SOUNDED LOUD AND BEAUTIFUL .
I JUST WENT IN THAT DIRECTION .
IN FACT , YOU DON 'T QUITE KNOW .
I WANT TO SEE MY GRANDFATHER , MISS HOLLOWAY .
YOU WILL , IN TIME .
DOES GRANDFATHER KNOW WHAT THIS PLACE IS LIKE ?
THAT WOMAN WHO LAUGHS .
I HEAR LAUGHING ALL NIGHT !
AND THAT OTHER WOMAN THAT- -
YOUR GRANDFATHER 'S SORRY THAT YOU HAVE TO BE HERE ,
BUT HE KNOWS YOU 'LL BE BETTER SOON .
BETTER ?
BUT I 'M PERFECTLY ALL RIGHT !
I WOULDN 'T SAY THAT , STELLA , DEAR .
AND PLEASE DON 'T KEEP ASKING TO SEE ME .
WHY DO YOU HATE ME , MISS HOLLOWAY ?
YOU SEE- -
YOU DO FEEL PERSECUTED .
RICK , IF I SHOULD EVER HAPPEN TO LOSE MY MIND- -
I DON 'T THINK YOU 'LL LOSE IT . IT MIGHT RATTLE TO ONE SIDE .
BUT IF I DO , NO MARY MEREDITH RETREAT FOR ME .
PLAIN , OLD-FASHIONED LUNATIC ASYLUM ,
NOT THAT CREEPY HORROR !
YOU 'LL HAVE A LOVELY TALK WITH MISS HOLLOWAY ONCE A WEEK .
- BRRR . - YOU THINK SHE WAS LYING TO US ?
ABOUT THE PAST ? WHY SHOULD SHE ?
SHE WASN 'T GOING TO TELL US ABOUT THE BABY . AND LATER , SHE MADE THAT ONE BREAK .
ADMITTING IT WAS MARY WHO TOLD CARMEL TO GO .
WHY TRY TO HIDE IT ? IT WAS A NORMAL HUMAN REACTION .
MADE ME LIKE MARY BETTER , AS A MATTER OF FACT .
I WAS GETTING AWFULLY BORED WITH HER PERFECTION .
WHY WOULD MISS HOLLOWAY WANT TO TURN HER INTO A PLASTER SAINT ?
MAYBE SHE LIKES PLASTER SAINTS .
SHE 'S ONE HERSELF .
THANK YOU , DOCTOR .
I ASSURE YOU THAT WHEN THAT HEALTHY YOUNG MAN LAUGHS ,
- HE ISN 'T BEING DELIRIOUS . - GOODBYE , DOCTOR .
OH , HELLO ! COME IN .
HELLO .
- WHAT NEWS WI TH STELLA ? - NONE , AND I WON 'T BE HAVING ANY .
HER GRANDFATHER 'S KICKED ME OUT .
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ALL DAY ?
TO THE MIDDLE OF BODMIN MOOR AND BACK .
- SEEING A MISS HOLLOWAY . - WHAT ? HOLY HOLLOWAY
OF " WEALTH THROUGH HARMONY " ?
- WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT HER ? - NOTHING REALLY ,
EXCEPT THAT DR. RUDD , MY PREDECESSOR ,
HAD SOME SORT OF PREJUDICE AGAINST HER .
SHE SAYS CARMEL KILLED MARY MEREDITH .
YES , SHE WAS THERE . NURSED CARMEL AFTERWARDS .
COULD WE TALK TO DR. RUDD ABOUT HER ?
ONLY IF WE HAVE ANOTHER SEANCE .
- I WONDER- - - WHAT ?
IT 'S ONLY THE VERY FAINTEST CHANCE ,
OF COURSE , BUT COME ON UPSTAIRS .
1908 TO ' 11 , '12 TO ' 15 ,
'16 TO ' 19 . HERE WE ARE .
IT HAPPENED IN THE WINTER .
Scott : YES , LET 'S START WITH NOVEMBER .
Pam : FROM HIS HANDWRITING ,
DR. RUDD MUST HAVE BEEN 200 YEARS OLD .
MEASLES , MEASLES , MEASLES ,
WHOOPING COUGH , MEASLES , APPENDICITIS .
PLEASANT CHANGE FOR THE OLD BOY .
HERE WE ARE .
CALLED TO WINDWARD HOUSE .
MEREDITH 'S MODEL , CARMEL QUESADA , DOUBLE PNEUMONIA .
QUESADA GIRL MUCH WORSE .
NO ATTEMPT TO WARM THE BEDROOM .
FOUND TRACES OF SNOW ON THE FLOOR .
SNOW ? THEN THE WINDOW WAS LEFT OPEN .
SPOKE SEVERELY TO NURSE .
RETURNED TO WINDWARD THIS EVENING .
PATIENT DEAD .
NURSE HOLLOWAY THREATENED ME
WITH LEGAL ACTION WHEN I USED THE WORDS ,
" CRIMINAL NEGLIGENCE . "
- BUT THAT MEANS- - - TO A DOCTOR OF RUDD 'S GENERATION ,
IT WAS VERY APT TO MEAN MURDER .
MISS HOLLOWAY MURDERED CARMEL ?
- Servant : DOCTOR . - IN A QUIET , LADYLIKE WAY .
- DOCTOR ! - YES , EDITH ?
THE COMMANDER 'S MAID 'S ON THE PHONE .
YOU 'RE TO COME AT ONCE .
- IS IT MISS MEREDITH ? - IT 'S THE COMMANDER .
TOOK AWFUL BAD , THE MAID SAYS .
ALL RIGHT , EDITH . YOU TAKE THIS HOME .
THERE MAY BE SOME OTHER DETAILS . I 'LL BE ALONG LATER .
HE 'S IN HERE , DOCTOR .
I UNDID HIS SHOES . IT WAS ALL I KNEW HOW TO DO .
- BAD ONE THIS TIME , SCOTT . - YES , I KNOW .
HOLD THAT UNDER HIS NOSE .
( coughs )
WANT AN APOLOGY , SCOTT ?
YOU 'D GET IT ,
- IF YOU STUCK OUT FOR IT . - NO , THANKS .
I 'LL HAVE YOU RIGHT IN A JIFFY .
WHO 'S THERE ? !
Rick : NOW WHO DO YOU SUPPOSE IS THERE ?
HELLO , LIZZIE .
I 'M SITTING IN YOUR MOTHER 'S CHAIR ,
AND IF ANY GHOST COMES ALONG ,
I 'LL LET OUT A SCREAM THAT WOULD FRIGHTEN THE LIFE OUT OF IT .
WHAT 'S HAPPENED ?
I FEEL THE WICKEDNESS OF THIS HOUSE GATHERING AROUND .
COME ON , NOW . HOP OFF TO THE JESSUPS .
I 'M NOT GOING . I 'LL BE FOUND DEAD IN ME BED IN THE MORNING ,
STIFF WITH FRIGHT , AND ME DEATH WILL BE ON YOU .
- ME ? ! - HOW DO I KNOW WHAT DEVILMENT
YOU 'LL BE UP TO WHEN ME BACK IS TURNED ?
I PROMISE YOU WE 'LL DO NOTHING TONIGHT
THAT THE PRIEST WOULDN 'T APPROVE OF .
LORD BLESS YOU , MR. RICK .
I WAS HOPING YOU 'D SAY THAT .
I 'LL GO AND GET ME HAT AND COAT .
FIND ANYTHING NEW ?
NOTHING AFTER THAT ENTRY .
HOW ABOUT A WHISKEY AND SODA ?
LESS SODA THAN USUAL , THANKS .
Pam : AWFUL IF WE TOOK TO DRINK , BOTH OF US .
Rick : WELL , IT 'S AN IDEAL HOUSE FOR DELIRIUM TREMENS .
BEFORE YOU TAKE A SIP ,
DON 'T YOU SMELL MIMOSA ?
YES .
ARE YOU SCARED ?
I WISH I 'D WAKE UP .
IT CAME FROM THE NURSERY LAST NIGHT .
YOU HAVE THE GREAT NOSE OF THE FAMILY .
NOT A TRACE OF IT NOW .
- IT 'S STRONGEST HERE . - IT 'S ALMOST OVERPOWERING .
I WISH YOU 'D TELL US WHAT YOU WANT , MARY MEREDITH !
- Lizzie : MR. RICK ? - YES ?
I FORGOT TO ASK .
DID YOU FIND OUT ANYTHING TODAY ?
JUST TURNED UP A COUPLE OF MURDERS .
HOLY SAINTS PRESERVE US .
- ( doorbell rings ) - ANSWER THE DOOR .
IT 'S PROBABLY DR. SCOTT .
- GOOD EVENING , DR. SCOTT . - EVENING , LIZZIE .
- IN HERE . - GOOD NIGHT , MISS PAM .
- GOOD NIGHT . - GOOD NIGHT .
- I 'M GLAD TO FIND YOU HERE . - HOW 'S THE COMMANDER ?
IT 'S NOT HIM I 'M WORRIED ABOUT . IT 'S STELLA .
- WHAT 'S THE MATTER WITH HER ? - SHE 'S AT MISS HOLLOWAY 'S .
- NO ! - WE CAN 'T LET HER STAY THERE . WE 'VE GOT TO GET HER TONIGHT .
THAT 'S THE WAY I FEEL , BUT DON 'T LET 'S GET HYSTERICAL .
MISS HOLLOWAY WAS HER MOTHER 'S BEST FRIEND .
THE IDEA OF HER SPENDING AN HOUR IN THAT PLACE IS HORRIBLE .
CAN YOU GET THE OLD BOY 'S PERMISSION ?
HE 'S FAR TOO ILL . WE 'VE NO AUTHORITY WHATEVER .
- THEN WE 'LL DO IT WITHOUT . - SHALL WE TAKE THE CASEBOOK ?
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO FRIGHTEN HER WITH IT .
YES . NO , WAIT- -
WE 'LL DESCRIBE WHAT WE FOUND AND THEN PILE IT ON A BIT , HUH ?
LET 'S GO TO A TELEPHONE .
YES ?
YES .
IT 'S NO BOTHER AT ALL , MISS FITZGERALD .
I 'LL BE GLAD TO SEE YOU AGAIN .
ARE YOU MOTORING ?
IN TWO HOURS .
GOODBYE .
BRING IN MISS MEREDITH .
I MAY NEED THE CAR THIS EVENING .
GOOD EVENING , MY DEAR .
COME IN .
SIT DOWN .
I THOUGHT YOU 'D FEEL MORE AT HOME HERE .
I DO , MISS HOLLOWAY .
I 'VE BEEN GIVING YOUR PROBLEM
THE MOST SERIOUS CONSIDERATION .
IT 'S NOT MUCH OF A PROBLEM .
I JUST WANT TO GO HOME .
TO YOUR GRANDFATHER 'S ?
I COULDN 'T PERMIT THAT .
YOU 'VE NEVER BEEN VERY HAPPY THERE .
WHERE WOULD YOU REALLY LIKE TO BE ?
YOU MEAN WINDWARD ?
THAT 'S THE BASIS OF ALL YOUR TROUBLE ,
BEING KEPT AWAY FROM THERE .
DO YOU THINK SHE WANTS YOU THERE ?
YES , I THINK SHE DOES .
AND WHAT SHE WANTS , I WANT .
I 'VE TALKED WITH THE FITZGERALDS .
THEY 'RE VERY FOND OF YOU .
THEY 'LL LET ME STAY THERE WITH THEM ?
FOR THE PRESENT , YOUR GRANDFATHER 'S
NOT TO KNOW THAT YOU 'VE LEFT HERE .
IT WOULD WORRY HIM .
YOU MUST GO STRAIGHT TO WINDWARD .
IS THAT CLEAR ?
MISS HOLLOWAY ,
I 'M THE HAPPIEST PERSON IN THE WORLD .
THERE 'S A TRAIN IN 40 MINUTES .
MY CAR WILL TAKE YOU TO THE STATION .
GOOD EVENING . WON 'T YOU COME IN ?
OH , BUT I MUST ANNOUNCE YOU !
DON 'T BOTHER . WE 'LL ANNOUNCE OURSELVES .
GOOD EVENING .
SO YOU 'VE THOUGHT OF SOME MORE QUESTIONS ?
WHY DIDN 'T YOU TELL US STELLA WAS HERE ?
THE PRESENCE OF MY GUESTS IS CONFIDENTIAL .
- WE 'VE COME TO TAKE HER . - THIS IS STELLA 'S DOCTOR .
OH , I BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND .
THIS IS A RESCUE PARTY .
I MUST ASK YOU TO TAKE ME TO STELLA AT ONCE .
THERE WAS A TIME WHEN I WOULD HAVE RESENTED
SUCH IMPERTINENCE , PARTICULARLY FROM A DOCTOR
WHOSE CONDUCT LEAVES SO MUCH TO BE DESIRED .
PLEASE STOP BEATING ABOUT THE BUSH .
I COULDN 'T BE ANGRY WITH ANYONE TONIGHT .
YOU KNOW THOSE MOMENTS WHEN THE LIGHT IS VERY CLEAR ,
WHEN THE SCALES AT LAST SWING
INTO PERFECT BALANCE .
- WHERE IS STELLA ? ! - TELL THEM , MISS ELLIS .
SHE 'S ON THE TRAIN FOR BIDDLECOMBE . THE 9 : 20 .
ON HER WAY HOME .
- IS THAT TRUE ? - SHE 'LL BE THERE LONG BEFORE YOU .
- WHAT HAPPENED ? - NOTHING HAPPENED .
SHE WASN 'T VERY HAPPY HERE .
I CAN 'T BE OF ANY HELP TO PEOPLE WHO ARE UNHAPPY .
SHE WENT TO HER GRANDFATHER 'S ?
- NO . - NOT TO WINDWARD HOUSE .
BETTER THAN THAT .
TO THE CLIFF ...
AND THE ROCKS BELOW THE CLIFF .
- YOU LET HER ? ! - THAT 'S WERE MARY WENT .
THAT 'S WHERE SHE DIED .
SHE 'S OUT OF HER MIND . COME ON !
STELLA HAS A 20-MINUTE START !
Holloway : SHE HAD SUCH A LONELY SOUND .
EVERY SEVENTH WAVE .
- YOU 'D BETTER LOOK AFTER HER . - MISS HOLLOWAY !
WHAT 'S THE MATTER , MISS HOLLOWAY ?
GET OUT OF THIS ROOM !
I 'VE DONE WHAT SHE WANTED AT LAST .
HAVEN 'T I , MARY ?
IT 'S ALL STRAIGHT NOW .
THERE ARE NO FRAYED EDGES .
NO LOOSE ENDS .
ALL STRAIGHT .
ALL SMOOTH .
THESE LOCAL TRAINS ARE VERY SLOW , YOU KNOW .
BUT THIS ONE HAD A HEAD START .
YOU NEEDN 'T WORRY . SHE CAN 'T GET INTO THE HOUSE .
YOU DID LOCK THE DOOR , DIDN 'T YOU , PAM ?
NO , I THOUGHT YOU DID .
- WILL YOU BE ALL RIGHT ? - OH , YES .
I 'LL BE ALL RIGHT , NOW . I 'LL BE WITH MY FRIENDS .
( bells jingle )
PAMELA !
RICK !
PAMELA , ARE YOU THERE ?
WHERE ARE YOU , PLEASE ?
( groaning )
LIZZIE ?
IS THAT YOU ?
Commander : STELLA .
STELLA .
GRANDFATHER !
STELLA , MY CHILD .
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE ?
SOMEONE TELEPHONED
FROM MISS HOLLOWAY 'S .
AND YOU WALKED ALL THAT WAY ?
WELL , I HAD TO GET HERE .
DON 'T TRY AND TALK , DARLING . I 'LL GET DR. SCOTT .
OH , DEAR THERE 'S NO TELEPHONE IN THIS HOUSE .
GO . GO !
YOU CAN 'T BE LEFT ALONE .
BUT THE DANGER IS FOR YOU .
PLEASE GET OUT OF THIS HOUSE , NOW .
NOW LIE BACK QUIETLY .
I 'M NOT AFRAID OF ANYTHING HERE .
THEN BE AFRAID !
BE AFRAID , FOR HEAVEN 'S SAKE .
WHEN YOU WERE A LITTLE CHILD ,
AFTER HER DEATH ,
THE EVILS OF THIS HOUSE REACHED OUT FOR YOU .
I TOOK YOU AWAY THEN .
IF I COULD ONLY TAKE YOU NOW .
IT 'S ALL RIGHT , WE 'RE TOGETHER .
STELLA ! GO !
GRANDFATHER !
I WON 'T BE AFRAID , MOTHER .
( screams )
STELLA !
STELLA , STOP !
HOLD ON , DARLING .
WE 'VE GOT YOU NOW .
HANG ON .
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
- YES . - SURE ?
DR. SCOTT , GRANDFATHER 'S IN THE STUDIO .
HE 'S TERRIBLY ILL .
WE 'D BETTER GET TO HIM AT ONCE .
THERE 'S NOTHING I CAN DO , MY DEAR .
I KNEW .
SHE KILLED HIM JUST AS SHE TRIED TO KILL ME .
- MY OWN MOTHER ! - NO , STELLA .
BUT I TELL YOU I SAW MY MOTHER
JUST AS MY FATHER PAINTED HER .
- IT MUST HAVE BEEN CARMEL . - IT WASN 'T .
STEADY , STELLA .
UNLESS- -
UNLESS PERHAPS MISS HOLLOWAY WAS RIGHT .
PERHAPS IT 'S MY MIND .
- OH , RICK ! - NO , DARLING , NO .
THE MIMOSA SCENT , IT 'S FLOODING THE ROOM .
IT 'S ALL RIGHT , DARLING . NOTHING WILL HURT YOU .
BUT I 'M NOT FRIGHTENED .
THIS IS WHAT I FELT IN THE NURSERY THAT NIGHT .
THE BOOK !
WHAT 'S DOING IT ?
Dr. Scott : THE WIND .
Pam : BUT WHAT ABOUT THE MIMOSA ?
WE 'RE LETTING OUR IMAGINATIONS
PLAY HOB WITH OUR SENSES .
11 : 15 A.M. MARY ANN HARDY .
BROKEN ARM . SECOND THIS YEAR .
IT 'S IMAGINATION , ALL RIGHT .
WHAT DID I EXPECT ?
WAIT A MINUTE .
3 : 20 P.M. , CALLED TO WINDWARD HOUSE
TO ATTEND MEREDITH 'S MODEL WHO HAD FAINTED .
IT DIDN 'T TAKE MUCH SKILL TO FIND THE REASON .
GIRL IN POOR PHYSICAL CONDITION ,
BUT I 'M SURE HER GREAT HAPPINESS WILL CARRY HER THROUGH .
THEN CARMEL HAD A BABY , TOO ?
5 : 10 P.M. MRS. MEREDITH CAME TO SEE ME .
EXPECTED TEARS , HYSTERIA .
INSTEAD , ICY CONTROL AND A DOMINATING DESIRE
THAT THE GIRL 'S CONDITION BE KEPT SECRET .
I SHOULD HAVE MORE SYMPATHY WITH THE LADY
IF I DID NOT KNOW HOW SHE HERSELF HAS FEARED
AND REFUSED MOTHERHOOD .
WHAT CAN IT ALL MEAN ?
WHERE WERE YOU BORN , STELLA ?
- IN PARIS . - WHERE THEY TOOK CARMEL
BEFORE THEY CAME BACK WITH THEIR BABY .
Pam : BUT SURELY YOU DON 'T THINK- -
I THINK MARY ADOPTED CARMEL 'S CHILD ,
GAVE HER A HOME AND A NAME ON THE CONDITION
CARMEL NEVER CAME BACK HERE .
SHE COULDN 'T LIVE UP TO IT . SHE HAD TO BE NEAR HER BABY .
BUT RICK , IT DOESN 'T FIT .
THE MIMOSA SCENT THAT COMES WITH THE GENTLE GHOST ,
THAT WAS MARY 'S SCENT . STELLA 'S FATHER TOLD HER .
NO .
NO , MY FATHER ONLY WROTE IT WAS MY MOTHER 'S SCENT .
I 'M CARMEL 'S CHILD .
STELLA , DON 'T MIND TOO MUCH .
MIND ?
CAN 'T YOU SEE WHAT IT 'S DONE FOR ME ?
ALWAYS THERE 'S BEEN SOMETHING FIGHTING IN ME ,
SOMETHING THAT COULDN 'T BE CALM
AND COLD LIKE MARY .
I CAN BE MYSELF NOW .
THAT 'S WHAT SHE 'S WAITED ALL THESE YEARS TO TELL YOU .
OH , MOTHER , NOW I KNOW !
( Carmel laughing )
SHE 'S HAPPY NOW .
THE SCENT 'S GONE .
SHE WON 'T CRY ANYMORE .
SHE 'S GONE FOREVER .
WILL YOU COME BACK TO MY HOUSE NOW ?
- PLEASE , STELLA . - COME ALONG , DARLING .
ALL RIGHT .
GET HER OUT THROUGH THE NURSERY , QUICK !
- WHAT IS IT , THE COLD ? - GO ON , PAM !
- WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO ? ! - HELP STELLA , PLEASE .
MARY MEREDITH ,
WHERE ARE YOU ?
IT 'S TIME SOMEBODY FACED THAT ICY RAGE OF YOURS .
WHAT DO YOU WANT ?
IT 'S STELLA , ISN 'T IT ?
IT 'S TOO LATE , MARY .
YOU SEE ,
WE 'RE ON TO YOU NOW .
YOU TOLD CARMEL TO CLEAR OUT AND LEAVE HER BABY ,
BUT MEREDITH WOULDN 'T STAND FOR IT .
AND TO SPITE THEM , YOU TRIED TO KILL THEIR CHILD ,
AND INSTEAD WENT HURTLING OVER THE CLIFF YOURSELF .
GIVES YOUR SAINTLY LEGEND RATHER A BLACK EYE , DOESN 'T IT ?
OH , SO YOU DON 'T LIKE THE SOUND OF LAUGHTER , DO YOU ?
BUT THAT 'S ALL YOU 'LL GET FROM NOW ON .
I SHOULD THINK YOU 'D BE ON YOUR WAY NOW .
WE 'VE HAD ENOUGH .
WE 'RE NOT FRIGHTENED OF YOU ANYMORE .
FROM NOW ON THIS HOUSE IS FOR THE LIVING !
( knocking )
Pam : RICK , ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
Stella : LET ME IN , RICK !
- OH , RICK ! - YOU ALL RIGHT , FITZGERALD ?
YES , FINE . SHE 'S GONE , STELLA .
LOOK !
HE 'D NEVER GO NEAR THOSE STAIRS BEFORE .
BOBBY 'LL BE BACK TOMORROW .
I THINK WE 'LL BE HAVING OTHER PLANS FOR BOBBY .
YOU 'RE STILL SHAKING , RICK .
WELL , I 'VE HAD A NARROW ESCAPE .
SHE MIGHT HAVE BEEN MY MOTHER-IN-LAW .